導演：奧利弗·斯通
"The movie will begin in five moments"
這是我的故事，你知道嗎？
the mindless voice announced.
那是一群充滿焦慮的年輕人...
"All those unseated will await the next show."
在生活的泥淖裡掙扎吶喊的聲音
讓我們緩緩的 無精打采地進入演唱大廳在生活的泥淖裡掙扎吶喊的聲音
讓我們緩緩的 無精打采地進入演唱大廳
We filed slowly, languidly into the hall.
在生活的泥淖裡掙扎吶喊的聲音讓我們緩緩的 無精打采地進入演唱大廳
讓我們緩緩的 無精打采地進入演唱大廳在生活的泥淖裡掙扎吶喊的聲音
We filed slowly, languidly into the hall.
在生活的泥淖裡掙扎吶喊的聲音
The auditorium was vast and silent.
周圍的一切既悠遠又寧靜
當我們表情陰沉地入座之後 掌聲響起來周圍的一切既悠遠又寧靜
當我們表情陰沉地入座之後 掌聲響起來
As we seated and were darkened, the voice continued.
周圍的一切既悠遠又寧靜當我們表情陰沉地入座之後 掌聲響起來
當我們表情陰沉地入座之後 掌聲響起來周圍的一切既悠遠又寧靜
As we seated and were darkened, the voice continued.
周圍的一切既悠遠又寧靜
"The program for this evening is not new.
今晚的節目並不新穎
今晚的節目並不新穎今晚的節目並不新穎
"The program for this evening is not new.
今晚的節目並不新穎
You've seen this entertainment through and through.
你或許已經一遍又一遍地欣賞過它
你或許已經一遍又一遍地欣賞過它你或許已經一遍又一遍地欣賞過它
You've seen this entertainment through and through.
你或許已經一遍又一遍地欣賞過它
You've seen your birth, your life and death.
你將從中體味到你的生命 生活與死亡
你將從中體味到你的生命 生活與死亡你將從中體味到你的生命 生活與死亡
You've seen your birth, your life and death.
你將從中體味到你的生命 生活與死亡
You might recall all of the rest.
回憶起所有的休止符
Did you have a good world when you died?
當你死去的時候
當你死去的時候當你死去的時候
Did you have a good world when you died?
當你死去的時候
Enough to base a movie on?"
能夠擁有一個美好的空間嗎？
能夠擁有一個美好的空間嗎？能夠擁有一個美好的空間嗎？
Enough to base a movie on?"
能夠擁有一個美好的空間嗎？
Hey, Jim, it's your birthday, man.
嘿，吉姆，今天不是你的生日嗎？
What do you say we finish this another night?
我們下次再干吧
Turn the lights down a little bit more, will you, Jay?
約翰，我的歌怎麼樣？
Hey, man. How come the Doors aren't in on this?
嘿，夥計 樂隊用門這個名字你看行不行？
No music. No Doors. Come on, let's roll.
別提音樂也別提門了，到此為止
Rolling.
好了
ls everybody in?
人人都在嗎？
The ceremony is about to begin.
儀式就要開始了
Let me tell you about heartache...
讓我來告訴你如何生活
以及上帝的消失 片名：大門讓我來告訴你如何生活
以及上帝的消失 片名：大門
and the loss of God.
片名：大門以及上帝的消失 片名：大門
以及上帝的消失片名：大門
and the loss of God.
片名：大門
Wandering, wandering in hopeless night.
在毫無希望的夜晚四處徘徊
Out here, in the perimeter, there are no stars.
讓我來告訴你們 在這個世界上所有的明星中
Out here, we is stoned, immaculate.
誰才是奇才
"1949年，新墨西哥"誰才是奇才
"1949年，新墨西哥"
lt's beautiful. Look at those big, puffy clouds.
我們都在這塵世間酩酊大醉
Hey, Jimmy. Wake up. Look at the clouds.
嘿，吉米，醒醒
Come on. Wake up.
吉米，醒醒
What's going on?
這些人怎麼啦？
l don't know.
Officer, what happened? Can we help?
先生，我們來得真巧，需要幫忙嗎？
No, sir. We've got everything under control.
哦，不，你們過去吧
Just a dream, Jimmy.
太奇怪了
That's all it is. lt's just a dream
這一切對我來說太奇怪了
"1965年，加州威尼斯海灘"
Waiting for the medicine.
去喝點酒嗎？
On your finger.
我等了很久了
Wait here. Don't go.
好，我一會兒再來
l'll be right here.
好的
You got a problem with doors?
你怎麼不從門走？
Waste of time.
就這麼一次
l followed you from the beach.
我一直從海灘跟你到這兒
You followed me?
跟著我？
- Why? - 'Cause...
-為什麼？ -因為...
you're the one.
你知道為什麼
Maybe you should meet my old man.
或許你該成為我的情人
What's your name?
你叫什麼名字？
- Mine's Jim. - Pam.
-我叫吉姆 -我叫帕姆拉
Who the hell was that?
你剛才和誰在說話？
l have no idea.
我也不太清楚
Nietzsche said...
米切爾說過...
"All great things must first wear terrifying and monstrous masks..
所有偉大的東西起先 總是以可怕荒謬的面目出現的
"加州大學洛杉磯分校電影學校"所有偉大的東西起先 總是以可怕荒謬的面目出現的
"All great things must first wear terrifying and monstrous masks..
"加州大學洛杉磯分校電影學校" 我們用人類的心理所有偉大的東西起先 總是以可怕荒謬的面目出現的
"加州大學洛杉磯分校電影學校" 我們用人類的心理
in order to inscribe themselves...
所有偉大的東西起先 總是以可怕荒謬的面目出現的"加州大學洛杉磯分校電影學校" 我們用人類的心理
所有偉大的東西起先 總是以可怕荒謬的面目出現的
in order to inscribe themselves...
來描述它的自身所有偉大的東西起先 總是以可怕荒謬的面目出現的
來描述它的自身
on the hearts of humanity."
我們用人類的心理來描述它的自身
我們用人類的心理
Listen, children...
聽著，孩子們
to the sound of the Nuremberg night.
在這座大城市的夜晚
ln a seance...
這個...
the shaman leads a sensuous panic.
擅於煽動群眾情緒的領導者...
He acts like a madman. A professional hysteria.
引起了一場極端的恐怖
Have you ever seen God?
他的行為就像一個瘋子
Mandala?
像一個內行的...
A symmetrical angel.
歇斯底里者
We got our final vision by clap.
你們都已經看到過
Columbus' groin got filled with green death.
它所造成的痛苦傷害以至死亡
- l touched her thigh... - This film is weak.
你們看到這最後一幕了嗎？
and death smiled.
你們的熱情就快死去了
Hey, Morrison. Fuck them, man.
莫裡森，該死的人
lt's great. lt's nonlinear, it's poetry.
再沒有比這更可怕的了
lt's everything good art stands for.
這是一首史詩，你寫得真棒
This world, a monster of energy.
這個世界，巨大的能量
Without beginning, Without end.
你們擁有開始，你們也擁有結束
Likewise, without increase or income.
直到一無所有 這是非常正確的方式
Disclosing nothing.
我們從中獲取了印象和收益
This world.
這個世界
This world is a will to power...
這個世界擁有豐富的能量
and nothing besides.
此外，你別無所有
Pretty pretentious there.
吉姆，你成為大家注意的焦點了
Not easy to follow. A little incoherent.
我很想弄明白
Dancing bears, Nazism, masturbation.
你這片子裡的意思
What's next?
片子裡想證明的是怎麼樣的人物？
- What do you guys think? - A bore, man. l hated it.
同學們，你們怎麼看？
lt was better than a Warhol picture!
這當然是一副描寫事件的圖畫
lt was worse!
沒有這樣的事件存在!
A guy sleeping for seven hours?
一個具有指導性意義的...
There was no political conscience.
領袖人物
- You need your art spoon-fed to you. - Right on!
大家請安靜!
Hold it down. Let's ask the filmmaker what he thinks.
安靜，我來問問製片人
l quit.
我不上這課了
Awake.
出眾的人
Shake dreams from your hair, my pretty child, my sweet one.
從夢中醒來吧，我的寶貝
Choose the day and choose the sign of your day.
選擇一天，標上印記
The day's divinity. First thing l see.
這將會成為神聖的一天
Come on out for a walk.
出去散散步吧
lt's a beautiful night.
今晚的夜色很美
A vast, radiant beach...
閃閃發光的海灘
and a cool, jeweled moon.
寶石般的月亮
Couples, naked, race down by its quiet side.
裸露的人們成雙成對 在海灘上奔跑
And we laugh like soft, mad children...
我們像孩童般大笑
smug in the woolly, cotton brains of infancy.
小小年紀，自鳴得意
Every time l try to make love to you
每一次我想和你做愛
you run around with your mouth stuck out
你就大叫大喊地亂跑
Choose, they croon, the ancient ones. The time has come again.
遠古之物在輕聲低吟
Choose now, they croon, beneath the moon...
他們在月光下，在遠古的湖畔...
beside an ancient lake.
輕聲低吟
Enter again the sweet forest.
再一次進入可愛的森林
Enter the hot dream. Come with us.
跟我一起進入夢想
Everything is broken up...
世間萬物...
and dances.
紛紛起舞
l can't believe it's so beautiful.
其美麗讓我難以置信
"Now l have come again to the land of the fair, strong and the wise.
如今我又回到了那片土地 空氣和人群中
Brothers and sisters o'er the pale forest.
兄弟姐妹們在盡情地玩耍
O, children of night...
孩子們...
who among you will run with the hunt?
在你的四周追逐嬉戲
Now, night arrives with her purple legion.
如今我回到了魂牽夢縈的故鄉
Retire now to your tents and dreams.
明天要去我出生的地方
Tomorrow we enter the town of my birth.
那是令我復活的那塊土地
l want to be ready."
神秘又美麗
lt's beautiful.
太美了
- Do you like that? - lt's beautiful.
-真的嗎？ -太美了
l've never read much poetry before.
我以前沒讀過多少詩
What's a shaman?
薩滿是什麼？
He's a medicine man...
是個巫師
of the lndians.
印第安人
He gets into a peyote trance...
他能念讓陰魂附身的咒語
and he gets deeper and deeper, and then he has a vision...
很神秘是吧？的確，他能夠看透...
and the whole tribe is healed.
過去和未來
All cultures have a version of it.
所有的文化都有其變形
Greeks had theater and gods.
比劇院比上帝還要偉大
The lndians say the first shaman invented sex.
人們往往把這些人...
They called him "The One Who Makes You Crazy."
看作是最瘋狂的人
What turns you on?
你喜歡什麼？
l don't know.
我不知道
Experience.
體驗
Freedom.
自由
Love. Now.
愛和現在
You know, the first time l did acid, l saw God.
吉姆，現在我第一次 感到了上帝的存在
And l saw a friend of mine who was Christ and Judas too.
我看到朋友反目，互相敲詐
Then l realized that...
我並不認為...
that was the secret of everything.
世界上所有事情有什麼神秘
We're all one, the universe is one...
地球只有一個，宇宙也只有一個
and that everything is beautiful.
所有一切都是美麗的
l feel most alive...
我常常感到
confronting death...
生命和死亡是緊緊相連的
experiencing pain.
死亡是很美的事情
l think you're most alive by recognizing beauty.
我認為生活是美麗的 這還說得過去
Seeing truth.
死亡
Does death turn you on?
難道
You love death?
你愛死亡嗎？
Life hurts a lot more.
我感覺過好多次了
When you die, the pain's over.
沒有痛苦的死亡
All the poems have wolves in it.
印第安巫師都說過類似的話
All but one.
將死亡描述為...
The most beautiful one of all.
最美的東西
"She dances in a ring of fire...
她沿著火堆轉圈跳舞
and throws off the challenge with a shrug."
顯示出一種挑戰心理
That's beautiful.
太美了
Who did you write that for?
讓我們試試
l wrote it for you.
我愛你
Try acid, Ray.
你想出...
lt's guaranteed.
法子了嗎？
Shit, Morrison.
你又來了
My last trip was a real bummer, man.
你淨幹些沒用的事
l never had a bummer on acid.
這話怎麼說？
l'm trying naturally high now.
不過我會努力的
Whatever works.
如果你能成為電影策劃人
Making movies at MGM yet?
我還會寫出不少歌詞
l got in to see the head of production.
那我的作品一定不少
He said, "Where's your script?" l said, "l don't need a script.
吉姆，不用劇本...
Godard doesn't use a script. He improvises."
就可以找到鏡頭前的感覺
The guy says, "Great. Who's Godard?"
太棒了，好傢伙，太棒了
l'm off movies, man.
老兄，從你的電影中甦醒過來吧
l went out to the desert. Got lost.
一切都會轉瞬即逝
l've been living up on Trick's rooftop.
我從來找不到什麼捷徑
- Got stuck on a chick. - So what else you doing?
-那還得依靠你 -你幹什麼？
Writing songs, poems. Stuff like that.
我寫歌曲，寫詩，就這些
You're writing songs?
你寫歌曲？
So let me hear one.
一定相當不錯了
l'm shy.
只是嘗試
- Sing it to me. - l can't sing.
-你別謙虛了 -隨你怎麼說
You sing better than Dylan?
我們可以幹得比拍電影還要好
Johnny's in the basement
任何事只要有了牢固的基礎...
Mixing up the medicine l'm on the pavement
便有好的結局
Thinking about the government
有我的幫助，你會達到事業的頂峰
Let me hear your words.
有什麼新詞嗎？
All right.
好吧
Let's swim to the moon
「讓我們向著月亮游泳」
Let's climb through the tide
「讓我們順著潮汐攀登」
Penetrate the evening
「穿透黑夜」
That the city sleeps to hide
「這城市躲在夜幕下」
Let's swim out tonight, love
「讓我們今晚出去游泳吧，寶貝」
lt's our turn to try
「是時候試試了」
Park beside the ocean
「把車停在沙灘上」
On our
「開始我們的...」
Moonlight drive
「夜光之旅」
Those are great fucking lyrics, man.
還真不錯
- Yeah? - Yeah. You write this?
這是你寫的？
You got others in here?
你的腦子裡還有其他的歌嗎？
A bunch, man. l got a whole concert in my head.
去你的，我也不知道 我的腦子裡都裝了些什麼
l can see it all.
好像淨是這些玩意兒
What the hell happened to you in the desert, man?
老兄，碰上你是我命中注定的
- Ecstasy and madness. - Let's get a band together...
靈感還在下一首歌呢
and make a million bucks!
多美的字句!
- l got tons of songs. - Things are about to explode.
你還能寫出不少這樣的作品
l can feel it in the air. People want to fight or fuck.
吉姆，如今人們都他媽的愛上了殺人
Love or kill. Vietnam is right out there.
在地球的那邊，在越南 一切都那麼的瘋狂
Sides are being chosen.
孩子們不明白真相
Everything's gonna flame. The planet is screaming for change.
都被阿靈頓公墓中 所謂的英雄給迷惑了
We gotta make the myths.
我真想改變這一切
There ought to be great orgies, man.
夥計，你既偉大又堅定
When Dionysus arrived in Greece, he made all the women mad.
這世界充滿了見利忘義的小人
Leaving their homes and dancing off into the mountains.
女人們走出家門四處遊蕩
There should be great, golden copulations in the streets of L.A.
人們知道這其中聯繫的奧秘嗎？ 真像是一幫無賴
We should call ourselves Dionysus.
這事已成定局
l got a name. Doors.
我已經知道該怎麼寫了
You mean "The Doors ln Your Mind"? The Huxley book?
就叫門 關起門來人們可以回想一切
- Doors of perception. Acid. - That's great.
門是一種感覺，是問題的核心 是問題的本質
The quote's from William Blake.
是的，門是一種感覺
"When the doors of perception are cleansed...
儘管它沉默寡言
things will appear as they truly are."
但它可以洞察一切
Mescaline experiments. Reducing the sugar flow to the brain.
我喜歡它
Come on!
來吧!
You know the day destroys the night
「白天摧毀黑夜」
Night divides the day
「黑夜分割白天」
Try to run
「試著奔跑」
Try to hide
「試著躲藏」
Break on through to the other side
「穿到門的另一邊」
What's the matter?
怎麼回事？
- lt just doesn't sound right. - l know that, John.
-我覺得這有點不像是首歌 -約翰，你那麼認為
Jim, stay in time.
吉姆，是節拍問題
l say we try that bossa nova beat.
我認為是鼓太快了點
l think it's hot.
我認為這歌挺棒的
l think the lyrics are kind of weird.
我想也是節拍的問題
You write one, man.
你們都這麼說
We need more songs anyway.
我可唱不出比這更好的了
l thought it was pretty good.
這歌挺好的
Let's go outside.
我們出去一會兒
l came up with something.
謝謝你，薩姆
A minor, then F sharp.
媽媽理解我的憂慮
You know that it would be untrue
「你知道這不是真的」
You know that l would be a liar
「你知道我是個騙子」
lf l was to say to you
「如果非要我說」
Girl, we couldn't get much higher
「寶貝，我們已到達高潮」
Come on, baby, light my fire
「來吧，寶貝，點燃我的愛火」
- G, A, D. - Pretty good. Pretty neat.
-「G，A，D」 -這首歌是你寫的吧？
Try to set the night on fire
「讓這個夜晚充滿愛火」
Great, Robby. You got nice changes in there.
很好，羅比，你修改得不錯
- Got anymore lyrics? - l got some.
-你們在偷偷的幹嗎？ -你喜歡嗎？
l call it "Light My Fire."
我意識到我現在很喜歡 自 己充滿激情的時刻
lf l'm gonna compete with your stuff, it better be about earth, snakes or fire.
這可不是什麼奉承話 火焰中的蛇
l like it. Sounds like the Byrds though.
我喜歡這個稱呼
But l like it. lt's good.
聽起來
A little Latin beat'll do it some justice.
就像是個非凡的人物一樣
Maybe put a couple long solos, like Coltrane on "My Favorite Things."
我喜歡它，很不錯 我們就這麼幹下去
Start over, man.
從頭開始吧
A minor, B minor. lt's jazz.
你得明白，你得明白
The time to hesitate is through
「不必再猶豫」
- Some kind of intro. - No time to wallow in the mire
-你是音樂的寶庫，知道嗎？ -「不必再沉溺」
Try now, we can only lose
「放手試試，別怕失敗」
And our love becomes a funeral pyre
「讓我們的愛變成乾柴烈火」
Come on baby, light my fire
「來吧，寶貝，點燃我的愛火」
-是這樣嗎？ -不，不過我喜歡「來吧，寶貝，點燃我的愛火」
-是這樣嗎？ -不，不過我喜歡
Try to set the night on fire
「讓這個夜晚充滿愛火」
- Can you give me-- - Try now, we can only lose
-羅比，你能給我... -「放手試試，別怕失敗」
Can you give me five minutes? l got to figure out some kind of intro.
你能給我五個月的時間 讓我把這些都弄好嗎？那麼長
- Let's let him work. You like that? - Yeah, l like Laguna Beach, man.
是的，就這樣，我喜歡
Funeral pyre.
焰，火焰
What do you think about when you play?
羅比，你對演出怎麼看？
l don't know.
這個，我可拿不準
Fish in my fish tank.
但願我們這班生手能如魚得水
- How about that acid tonight, man? - Not for me.
我想應該成功的，你明白這一點
- Not me, either. - Right here at Ray's house.
管他呢，我想讓我們去冒一次險
See what kind of trouble we can get into tonight.
我想那一晚肯定會非常有趣 不是嗎？
No way. You always get all the chicks.
任人評價吧，演砸了...
l always get the dogs.
有大伙擔著
Hey, l got it! Come on!
準備開始
l got it! l got the intro!
我想拿下樂譜
Hang on a second. John, count off in four, man.
練習一下，現在可以開始了
One, two, three.
1，2，3
ls that horny fucker in the black pants here tonight?
穿著黑褲子的那個帥哥今晚在嗎？
'6個月後，日落大道" 穿著黑褲子的那個帥哥今晚在嗎？穿著黑褲子的那個帥哥今晚在嗎？
ls that horny fucker in the black pants here tonight?
穿著黑褲子的那個帥哥今晚在嗎？
No l.D.'s, you can't get in.
"6個月後，日落大道" 沒有身份證，你不能進去
沒有身份證，你不能進去"6個月後，日落大道" 沒有身份證，你不能進去
No l.D.'s, you can't get in.
"6個月後，日落大道" 沒有身份證，你不能進去
Yeah, we chased our pleasures here
「我們來此追逐快樂」
Dug our treasures there
「尋找寶物」
Can't you still recall The time we tried
「你能否記得，我們努力的日子」
Break on through to the other side
「穿過門的另一邊」
Turn around, man. Come on, let them in.
唱吧，吉姆，你聽見了嗎？
l found an island in your arms
「我在你的臂彎裡找到了一個島嶼」
A country in your eyes
「在你的眼睛裡找到一個故鄉」
Arms that chain us Eyes that lie
「你的手臂鎖住我，眼睛在撒謊」
Break on through to the other side
「穿過門的另一邊」
All right
好
l'm a big fan! Give it to me!
我是你的歌迷!給我!
Made the scene
「製造大場面」
Week to week
「一周又一周」
Day to day Hour to hour
「一天又一天，一小時又一小時」
The gate is straight Deep and wide
「大門向你們敞開著」
Break on through to the other side
「穿過門的另一邊」
All right
好
Hi, Jim. Can l have your autograph?
吉姆，我聽過你所有的歌
- l don't know. Where do you want it? - Anywhere you want it.
-真的嗎？我不知道 -是真的
Leave it to me. l can take you all the fucking way.
小伙子們，你們唱得真不錯
- You blew my mind. - Did you like the music?
-看來前途無量啊 -你喜歡這音樂嗎？
l loved it. That's why we're talking.
音樂，我能愛音樂嗎？
Some of it's on the dark side. You ought to get some tunes.
那只是我彈的對象而已
Herman's Hermits stuff. Mrs. Brown, you've got a lovely daughter
只要與我合作
That shit goes right to the radio.
你們的身價很快就會大為不同的
l need him here to groove on my boyfriend.
好的 我會把這消息告訴我男朋友的
What about getting us some real equipment?
那我們現在該怎麼做呢？
l sign you to a five-year management contract--
我想你們最好還是找個經紀人
You with the joint. Put that out, please.
把它熄滅
- We can smell that upstairs. - l can get you there.
樓上都能聞到味道
Trust me for a while. What do you say?
比爾先生是可以信任的
We'll have a band meeting on it.
我們會開會商量這事的
We do everything unanimously or we don't do it.
要是你們不懷好意的話 我們絕不干
The Musketeers.
我們會很好合作的
l'm touched.
這點你們儘管放心
Let me tell you something. Loyalty don't pay the bills.
最好趕在明天
Think about it and call me tomorrow. Here's my card.
你們就把事情決定了 這是我的名片
Pay attention. You could get rich.
注意，發財的機會到了
- Are you blind? - How old are you?
-別放棄啊 -小伙子，你多大了？
- Twenty-one. - Get lost, will you?
-正是墮入愛河的年齡
l'll make this quick and to the point. lf you repeat it, l'll deny it.
我想我們還是盡快的進入正題吧
Drop those guys.
我們合作怎麼樣？
Jim's got to start facing the crowd if he's going to be our front man.
吉姆要是不干怎麼辦？等著瞧吧
He's just getting his confidence.
吉姆他肯定會同意的
- The guy never does what's rehearsed-- - Well, how does it feel?
-你又不是不知道他的脾氣 -感覺什麼？
lt feels great, but--
我感覺有點擔心
Your looks. Your voice. That's what's going to sell records.
你是個討人喜歡的幸運傢伙
We'll make a million bucks a year.
我們會讓人人都喜歡上你的
Call me. l'm right.
給我打電話，我會很高興的
Hey, man, let's go.
我們走吧
Do yourself a favor. Call Larry.
抓住機會
l like a guy who wears his soul on his face.
這就會有很多錢了
Whisky's next, man. l can feel it in my bones.
夥計，這只是開始 我感覺我們要發財了
l still think the lyrics are weird.
是個好傢伙
The days are bright
「白天很明亮」
And filled with pain
「充滿了痛苦」
Enclose me in your gentle rain
「用你的細雨把我包裹」
The time you ran
「你奔跑起來」
Was too insane
「很瘋狂」
We'll meet again
「我們會重逢」
The chicks are really digging you tonight, man.
老兄，想要理解你的歌還真不容易
We still got to deepen, man.
你的歌還真有點深沉啊
- We got to go one more step. - Turn around and face the crowd.
-僅僅一步之遙 -你轉過身周圍那麼多人
lt'll help present it better.
你得去感覺
l got to go to the desert and take that peyote.
你把那些枯燥無味的歌手...
ls that what you're on?
都震住了
Yeah, man. lt's kicking in!
見鬼了，傻瓜!
- Fucking longhair! - He's fucking crazy.
滾開，讓我們去快活快活
- Come on. - l'm not doing acid, man.
-去你媽的 -夥計們夥計們
lt's peyote.
夥計們
What's a rock and roll band for?
你們看，咱們這幫搗蛋鬼
Let's plan a murder or start a religion.
咱們四個人組合得不錯啊
More, more, more!
我們樂意，夥計們!
l'm into T.M., man. l promised my guru.
我們得去瘋狂一回
l'll try it. l'm ready.
找些更多的，更多的女人，更多的妞
Let's go to the desert.
我們去沙漠吧
Let's do the peyote.
我們去佩約特吧
Who's on next?
接下來是誰？
Arthur Lee. He's cool.
亞瑟.李，他很棒
l am the lizard king!
我能為你們做一切!
l can do anything!
我給你們帶來了一些
Raise your hands if you understand.
快呀，如果你們聽懂了把手舉起來
Let's take a poll. How many of you know you're alive?
我說正因為你們熱愛生活
Bullshit!
就應該懂得把它拋棄!
You're plastic soldiers in a miniature dirt war.
我喜歡在恰當的時候 走近這骯髒的世界
Come on!
得了!
How many of you people know you're alive?
你們是怎樣熱愛這現實生活的？
Close your eyes.
考驗大家的時候到了
You see the snake.
這是一條像蛇一般...
See the serpent appear?
蜿蜒的道路
His head is ten feet long...
我們成群結隊
and five feet wide.
到這裡來尋求自身的感受
He has one red eye and one green eye.
這是尋求新鮮自我的地方
That's all right. lt gets better.
一會兒就會好的
Peace.
嗯...
Seven miles long.
有七英里長
Deadly.
它很長
See it. All the history of the world...
不是嗎？即使歷史在宇宙中的位置
is on its scales.
也是渺小微不足道的
All people. All actions.
人類的一切行為
We're all just little pictures in the scales.
都在生命的藍圖上留下了印記
God, it's big.
它是巨大的
lt's moving.
它是活躍的
Devouring consciousness.
孕育著紊亂可怕的力量
Digesting power.
非常恐怖的能量
Monster of energy.
它是個怪物
lt's a monster.
l'm gonna kiss the snake on the tongue.
輕輕觸摸著所有的人
Kiss the serpent.
輕輕觸摸著我
But if it senses fear...
這種直覺...
it'll eat us instantly.
使人們感受到...
But if we kiss it without fear...
它的無所不在
it'll take us through the garden.
毫無顧忌地輕輕觸摸
Through the gate.
從上帝到國王
To the other side.
到其他方方面面
Ride the snake...
通過這條...
'til the end of time.
時間之蛇
l think l'm fucked up, man.
我感到隱隱作痛，夥計
l'm not thinking right.
我能站起來嗎？
Look at your eyes, man. You're death.
我會死的
l'm afraid of my father.
我害怕我的父親
l can't be what they want me to be.
我擔心會發生令人震驚的事
Maybe you should kill your father.
或許他們會殺了你的父親
l'm in pain, man.
我是個很脆弱的人
l feel the universe functioning perfectly...
我感受到宇宙那無所不在的作用
but l'm still perfectly locked inside myself.
我看到了最完美的東西
lnstead of oneness, l feel isolation.
衣食可以解脫我們的孤獨
But you're alive.
你們難道喜歡恐怖嗎？
- Feel it. - l'm scared.
我感到害怕
- lt's beautiful. - l'm still scared.
-太美了 -我害怕
Then use us.
沒用的
Use our strength. Come on in here.
孩子，過來，你真沒用
That's right.
我們現在試試
We're a tribe now. A tribe of warriors.
試試更多的能力
l promise you, l'll be with you to the end of time.
向你保證 我將與你一同走向時間的終點
Nothing will destroy our circle.
我們圍在蛇的旁邊...
Ride the snake.
不再四處流浪
Come on.
好了，來呀
My wild love went riding
「我狂野的愛正在奔馳」
She rode all the day
「她整天騎著它」
She rode to the devil
「她騎著它奔向惡魔」
Asked him to pay
「讓他償還」
My wild love went riding
「我狂野的愛正在奔馳」
She went to the sea
「她騎著它奔向大海」
She went to the devil
「她騎著它奔向惡魔」
All that's left was we
「只留下我」
l'm lying. l am afraid.
我，我害怕了
Don't go away!
吉姆，別走開!
Come dance with me!
到我這兒來!
Where you going, Jimmy?
你願意到我這兒來嗎？
This is the end
「這是終點了」
Beautiful friend
「親愛的朋友」
This is the end
「這是終點了」
My only friend, the end
「我唯一的朋友」
Of our elaborate plans
「我們精心計劃的終點」
The end
「一切的...」
Of everything that stands
「終點」
The end
No safety or surprise
「無需驚訝」
The end
「終點」
l'll never look
「我絕不會...」
lnto your eyes
「再次...」
Again
看你的雙眼
Can you picture what we'll be
「你能描述我們的未來嗎？」
So limitless and free
「毫無限制，隨心所欲」
Desperately in need
「急切地需要...」
Of some stranger's hand
「陌生人的手」
ln a desperate land
「在絕望之地」
Lost in a Roman
「迷失在羅馬」
Wilderness of pain
「無盡的痛苦」
And all the children
"1966年 洛杉磯威士忌阿哥哥酒吧"
「所有的孩子...」"1966年 洛杉磯威士忌阿哥哥酒吧"
And all the children
"1966年 洛杉磯威士忌阿哥哥酒吧"
Are insane
「都瘋了」
Waiting for the summer rain
「等待著夏雨」
There's danger on the edge of town
「鎮上充滿危險」
Ride the king's highway, baby
「在國王的大路上奔馳」
Weird scenes inside the gold mine
「金山裡出現神秘場景」
Ride the highway west, baby
「在大路上往西奔馳」
Ride the snake
「騎著蛇」
To the lake
「到湖邊」
The ancient lake, baby
「那遠古的湖邊」
The snake is long
「那蛇很長」
Seven miles
「足有七英里」
Ride the snake
「騎著蛇」
He's old
「它很老」
And his skin is cold
「它的皮很冷」
The west is the best
「西方乃極樂世界」
Get here and we'll do the rest
「到達那裡便不必煩惱」
The blue bus
「憂鬱的汽車」
ls calling us
「在召喚我們」
Driver, where you taking us
「司機，你要把我們帶向何方」
The killer awoke before dawn.
「殺手在黎明前醒來」
He put his boots on.
「他穿上靴子」
He took a face...
「他看了一眼...」
from the ancient gallery...
「遠古的畫廊」
and he walked on down the hall.
「然後他走向大廳」
He went into the room where his sister lived.
「他走進他妹妹住的房間」
Then he...
「然後」
paid a visit to his brother.
「他看了看他的弟弟」
Then he--
「然後」
He walked on down the hall.
「他繼續往大廳走」
And he came to a door.
「他來到一堵門前」
He looked inside.
「他往裡看」
"Father." "Yes, son?"
「爸爸」「怎麼了，孩子？」
"l want to kill you."
「我要殺了你」
"Mother."
「媽媽」
l want to
「我想要...」
fuck you all night, baby
「整夜地操你」
Come on, baby
「來吧，寶貝」
"Mother, l want to fuck you"?
「媽媽，我想要操你？」
Come on
「來吧」
Fuck, fuck
「操，操」
Turn him off! Turn his fucking amp off!
關掉!把他的音箱關掉!
Fuck me, baby
「操我，寶貝」
Come on, baby
「來吧，寶貝」
- He's insane! - He's a great artist!
-他瘋了! -他是個偉大的藝術家!
- We all love it! - Come on
-我們愛你! -「來吧」
All right
「來吧」
Kill
「殺」
Get him out of here!
把他趕出去!
- Get the fuck out of here! - Kill the father.
他媽的，你給我放開
Nobody's gonna fuck their mother on my stage!
去你媽的，你這個狗雜種
- That's what l mean! - You're out of here!
你給我放開，給我放開
Kill your father! Fuck the mother!
去你媽的，放開我
All right!
來吧
Jerry, come on, man!
來吧，來吧
- Art, man! lt's art! - What do you know about art?
-你給我滾出去! -我要唱，我要唱
Take a look at the future, old man!
他媽的，我還要唱
We're things to come!
你聽見了嗎？
Here's art.
你這個狗雜種
- There's your art! - This is fucking great!
-我還要唱! -好啊，你們這幫混蛋
- We'll never work in this town again. - Quite a night.
行了，這幫混蛋 我們不能再唱這種歌了
l'm Jac Holzman.
你們好，我叫傑克遜
- l own Elektra Records. - ls that asshole gonna pay us?
-我擁有一個唱片公司，是嗎？ -我要唱
l think if you can put what you did in there on record...
首先 我認為你們得改變一些演唱方式
we could really have something and make a lot of money.
你們可能還不瞭解唱片 對成名的作用
Rothchild here was born to be your producer.
你們可以灌一些好唱片 可以賺很多錢
How you doing? Sorry about all this. You guys are--
讓理查給你們介紹吧 你們好，小伙子們
Bertolt Brecht. lt's cabaret. lt's rock and roll.
我認為搖滾樂從來就是 瘋狂的吼叫扭捏作態
l'm really blown away, guys.
我很熟悉這些東西
l'd like to get you guys into a studio immediately.
要唱得柔和一點 你們打算馬上開始嗎？
How would you like to come down from there and make a record?
莫裡森，快下來，你要休息
Sure. Pretty good. Pretty neat.
當然，為什麼不呢，快下來
Bruce, you feel it?
效果不錯
lt's bitchin'.
是啊，效果不錯
An album of killer music in six days. Six days, baby.
我們還有六天的時間呢
Unreal.
「不真實的」
The time to hesitate is through
「讓時間去證明」
No time to wallow in the mire
「而時間顯得多麼珍貴」
Try now, we can only lose
「現在，我們沒有東西可失去」
And our love become a funeral pyre
「我們的愛，變成了墳墓」
Come on, baby, light my fire
「來吧，點燃我的火焰」
Try to set the night on fire
「把夜晚也點燃」
"1967年，舊金山" 「把夜晚也點燃」「把夜晚也點燃」
Try to set the night on fire
"1967年，舊金山"「把夜晚也點燃」
"1967年，舊金山"
L.B.J.! L.B.J. !
L.B.J.!
How many kids have you killed today?
「你今天殺了多少人？」
You know that it would be untrue
「你知道，一切都是不真實的」
You know that l would be a liar
「你知道，我是騙你的」
lf l was to say to you
「如果我要跟你說」
Girl, we couldn't get much higher
「女孩，我們要更興奮」
Come on, baby, light my fire
「來吧，點燃我的火焰」
Try to set the night on fire
「把夜晚也點燃」
All right!
好啊!
- Name? Occupation? - Bill Siddons. l'm the manager.
-姓名？職業？ -我是比爾.西登斯，經紀人
l manage the Doors.
我是大門的經紀人
- Name? Occupation? - Pamela Morrison. Ornament.
-姓名？職業？ -帕姆拉.莫裡森，形象設計
Robby Krieger. Guitar player.
羅比.克雷格，我是吉他手
John Densmore. Percussionist.
約翰.丹斯莫爾，鼓手
Twenty-two years old. Far out, man.
23歲
- Name? Occupation? - Raymond Daniel Manzarek.
-姓名？職業？ -雷蒙德.亞歷克斯
Born 2-12-39. Musician. Organist.
我是一個作曲家，演奏電子琴
- Name? Occupation? - Jim.
-姓名？職業 -吉姆
1967年，紐約
We're gonna be on TV.
我們要上電視了
Right this way, Mr. Sullivan.
沙利文先生
They're called the Doors...
我會把一切都安排好的
and they've got the number one single in the country right now.
好的，他們的樂隊叫大門
"Light Your Fire."
那首「點燃你的火焰」...
Now, they're not your usual group...
目前是全國最熱門的歌曲
but l think they're gonna fit in just fine.
「點燃我的愛火」
Everything's gonna be fine.
你是這麼說的嗎？
The riot continues in Detroit, with 1,400 buildings burned.
是的 現在你可以把一切都控制住了
No wonder "Light My Fire" is number one.
這是我最好的一首歌
So, what's your room number?
你的房間號碼是多少？
l'll talk to you later.
我以後會告訴你的
- You have got very serious hair. - Were you pinching her butt?
-這會兒還真嚴肅 -親愛的，你這麼認為嗎？
- What about me? - l won't open that kettle of worms.
我什麼呀？我想在這兒照張相
What about you, handsome? What can we do?
你對那些流言蜚語怎麼看？
Some of the worst mistakes of my life have been haircuts.
我想有些話會毀了我
Don't wash it. Don't set it. Go away. l like it just the way it is.
你別這樣梳，這種髮式不適合他
- Be mean. - Boys. Boys.
-好了，我走開 -小伙子們
Meet Mr. Sullivan.
來見見沙利文先生
Fellas, just great.
小伙子們
-l heard your record, "Light That Fire." -"Light Your Fire."
我聽過你們的唱片 今晚你們唱的那首...
- Just-- - "Light My Fire."
「火焰」
Fine. Just really, really fine.
「點燃你的火焰」 反正就是火焰，你來說吧
l have one small thing to bring up.
有一點小事要告訴你們
But it's important. The guys at network told us...
事情雖小，卻很重要 你們千萬得記住
they have a little problem...
有一個小小的問題就是
with the lyric, "Girl, we couldn't get much higher."
當你們和台下進行交流的時候
You can't say "higher"...
可別太出格
on network.
她們要問的話
They asked if you could say, instead...
你們可以說可以唱
"Girl, we can't get much better."
姑娘們，我們會幹得更好的
- Can you dig that? - How about...
你們明白嗎？
"Girl, you couldn't bite my wire"?
要是說，姑娘 你可別上我的鉤，怎麼樣
l don't think Standards and Practices would--
得了，我認為不要在舞台上 搞那些亂七八糟的玩意兒
Why don't you have a nice, big smile on your face when you get out there?
你們的表演要恰到好處
There's no point in being sullen.
放機靈一點，都得站在突出的位置
- You know what l mean? - We're a sullen group, Ed.
-但別太火爆了，明白了嗎？好好演吧 -難道要我們裝啞巴？
You boys should know, Mr. Sullivan is considering you for four more shows.
沙利文先生是想讓你們的演出 顯得更正規一些
- You dig? - We dig.
-明白嗎 -我們明白
l'll work it out. Just give me five minutes.
再給我們五分鐘時間
- Groovy. - Just give me five.
行了，好吧，但是請注意一點
Have a great show.
祝你們演出成功，就這樣
Well?
怎麼辦？
- Come on. - lt's just a word.
-得了，約翰 -是歌詞問題，吉姆
The Stones changed when they played here.
但是演出不能改了
Why don't you change your name to...
對，我們把名稱改為...
Sidney or lrving Manzarek?
悉尼艾爾文夥伴樂隊怎麼樣呢？
- lt's just a word. - Hey, man.
可還存在歌詞問題，夥計們
My words. l don't care. Let's just jam.
我不介意什麼歌詞，這取決於吉姆
And now...
現在
direct from Los Angeles, California...
來自加利福尼亞州洛杉磯的...
ladies and gentlemen, here now, the Doors!
搖滾樂隊門為大家演唱
You know that it would be untrue
「你知道這不是真的」
We're okay sound wise?
注意了，這是搖滾樂，明白了？
lf l was to say to you
「如果非得我說」
Girl, we couldn't get much higher
「女孩，我們已到達高潮」
He said it!
怎麼啦？
He said it on national TV.
他們怎麼唱這首歌
- l can't believe that! - Come on baby, light my fire
-我可不同意! -「來吧，寶貝，點燃我的愛火」
What's he doing? What's that?
為什麼不能唱？接著唱
Jesus! Get it off! You can see his thing!
-停下，你們趕快給我停下! -他們不是唱得很好嗎？
You blew it, you little shit!
你們這樣做是違反合同規定的
You'll never play Sullivan again!
你們趕快給我停下來!
Can you just move a step forward?
啊，好了，你能往前挪挪嗎？
Come on. l know you love to look at yourself.
過來，我知道你想突出這裝飾品
Great.
很好
Let's try something different. Take your shirt off.
讓我們試試別的姿勢，把襯衫脫了
- You take it off. - Do you need help?
-你來脫 -需要我幫忙
That's good.
很好
The camera is whatever you want it to be.
照相機可以拍出你想要的 任何一種照片
A woman you want to seduce.
吉姆，任何人想拍什麼樣的都行
A man you want to kill.
對一個想成為社會焦點的男人來說
lt can be anything you want.
相機是再適合不過的了
That's nice.
太好了
That's great!
Do you have any idea what these pictures can do?
太棒了，再來幾個動作
One image controls millions of people.
多拍幾張
- Where are the Doors? - Right here.
-門在哪裡？ -算了吧
Will you forget the Doors?
你得忘了門
You're the one they want.
你就是他們所需要的
You are the Doors. Come on.
來，別動，就這樣
That's it. Be ugly.
再來一張
l love that.
堅持一下
Anything you want.
好了，現在到那邊去，吉姆
There are no restrictions here.
吉姆，回過頭來看我
Look at yourself.
看看你自己
Fall in love with yourself.
愛上自己吧
You're your own audience now.
把大衣脫了
They want you.
他們想得到你
Worship, love you.
崇拜你，我愛你
Adore you.
崇拜你
Jim Morrison.
吉姆.莫裡森
The god of rock...
我得到了他
and cock.
Not tonight, Edie. Thank you, not tonight.
把你的工作和生活...
This is the fun part of my job. This is history in the making.
結合得很成功嘛
Would you like to see my imitation of a shrimp?
非常非常成功
Let me put it this way.
有時候我認為
Andy is more than an artist. Andy Warhol is art.
你給美國音樂帶來了新的生命
Sometimes l think bright people in America must ask themselves...
你會時不時地感到生活 被音樂融化了
"Does Andy imitate life, or does life imitate Andy?"
你會感到生活被音樂融化了
Jim, this is Tom Baker.
吉姆，這是湯姆.貝克
He's in one of Andy's movies, "l, A Man."
威尼斯電影演員
- And this is Count "Ruspooli." - Ruspoli.
-這位是科特.瑞斯佈雷 -瑞斯佈雷
He's ltalian, but he lives in Paris.
這是科特，他住在巴黎
He's from a very famous family, 700 years old.
一座有700多年歷史的著名城市
Hi, Jim. You are great.
-我叫吉姆 -很高興認識你
l see you at Ondine's with Hendrix.
我看了你的演出，真是意猶未盡啊
So cool.
太妙了，非常非常美妙
- All right. - Don't you like the way he talks?
難道你們只愛談這些...
- lt's so cool. - What's your trip?
非常美妙之類的話嗎？
My trip? l thought it was yours.
隱私
l caught your gig at The Scene. l thought it was pretty good.
我從來沒有見過像這樣唱歌的人
l liked it a lot. lt was hot.
我全身的血液都沸騰了
l like your movies, man. You got a great penis.
老兄，我也喜歡看你的電影
We're gonna split. Why don't you come with us?
在威尼斯你真棒
- We're going to get a bite to eat. - No, you can't leave.
吉姆，停一下，我們去和馬克談筆生意 -我怎能離開這裡呢？
Where's your will to be weird?
雷，這兒有這麼多的新朋友
Look, that's Jim Morrison.
我和他們正聊著呢
l like the Doors.
-生意要談，吉姆 -我喜歡門
Let's get out of here. These people are wacky.
-嘿，約翰，你認為他怪癖 -怪癖
Come with me. Andy's waiting for you.
我來給你們拍一張
No, not now. Let's do this later.
別這樣，你不能照
Do you remember San Francisco?
吉姆，你認為這就是你的目標嗎？
- No, not really. - Have another joint.
這個嘛，根本不是
Check it out.
吉姆
This chick here sings with Andy's band, The Velvet Underground.
-吉姆你得當心點 -你說什麼？
She says she can drink you under the table.
-那邊有個姑娘想認識你 -哦，是嗎
Hi, l'm Nico.
你好，我叫妮科爾
lt's so boring tonight.
今晚這兒太沒勁了
Some of us are going downtown to a new club.
有人進城去俱樂部了
You want to come?
你想去嗎？
Elevate your taste in trolls, man.
夥計，你得趕快決定啊
Vodka?
好
l'll race you.
我去
Your death.
好，我聽你指揮
Come on, man. Let's go.
你們怎麼了，啊
All right. We're gonna go to a club.
嘿，我們去俱樂部
l think this girl wants to hang out with you.
我真想和你們一塊去 你打算在那兒待多久
Don't you want to meet Andy Warhol?
10個鐘頭嗎？
l could do without the guy. He's a freak.
你們怎麼不跟著我，咱們走著去啊
Come on. We got a big gig tomorrow.
老兄，告訴你實話 我們很快就會把一切都安排好的
Wait. l thought we were going to be a rock and roll band.
等等我，我們的搖滾樂隊是四個人
All right. The four of us.
我們四個人一起去
Come on. This isn't our scene.
一群幻想家
These people are vampires.
Come on, let's make the myths. Remember?
哦，得了，別這樣
Let's go.
走吧
Don't leave.
你只會唱歌
Come on, you guys. Not tonight.
快呀，兄弟們
l don't know what'll happen.
今晚我們會知道發生什麼了
lt might be death.
我們會死的
lt's not death, man.
夥計，你不會死的
l'll see you tomorrow.
你現在成名人了
Jimmy, this way.
吉姆，上這兒來
Andy's waiting. This way. l'll take you to him.
安迪在等你呢
Hey, daddy.
哦，你好，吉姆
Jimmy, please. Come on.
呵呵
Andy's waiting. Come on.
哦，吉姆，咱們走吧
Hey, man. How you doin'?
從這邊走
All right. How you doin', man?
你好嗎？
Great.
好極了
Pretty good. Pretty neat.
我是吉姆.莫裡斯
There was this big show in Philadelphia.
吉姆這邊來，跟我來
Andy.
嘿，大家來認識一下
There were so many people there--
這是吉姆，吉姆.莫裡森
This is Jim Morrison of the world-famous Doors musical group.
是那個門樂隊的
- Andy Warhol, of course. - Hi. Wow.
你們都喜歡聽他的音樂
We really like your music.
我們非常喜歡聽你唱的歌
- How you doin', Andy? - Oh, great.
是這樣嗎，啊？
And there were so many people at the show...
我太喜歡了 演出現場有那麼多的觀眾
the paintings were getting crushed...
外間描述啊
and they had to take them all down.
他一定能造成轟動的
Really, they were kind of...
而且，有很多人都會這麼說的
great.
哦，太棒了
Just the walls. You see, Andy was the art.
真是很好
You should do a show with just bare walls.
你們也都見到他本人了 真的很不錯哦
We'd really like to use you in one of our movies, Jim.
哦，吉姆
You're really such a beauty.
這類讚賞通常都是留給電影的
Andy says someday everybody will be famous for 15 days.
你的歌，哦，實在是太美了
He'd really be great, wouldn't he?
沒人能像這樣 15天之內就聞名全國
l mean...
啊，我的意思
lt's the singer, not the song, right?
你真是太偉大了
lt's the astronaut, not the voyage.
有人給了我...
Somebody gave me this telephone.
這個電話
- l think it was Edie, wasn't it? - Yeah, it was Edie.
他說呀...
And she said that...
我能用它
l could talk to God with it...
和上帝交談
but l don't have anything to say.
我可沒那麼多話說
Here. This is for you.
那麼，就送給，送給你吧
Now you can talk to God.
現在你可以和上帝說話了
Morrison.
莫裡森
Come here.
過來
Darling, listen, l pay the bills...
太妙了，太妙了
so l can use any language that l want.
夥計，今晚過得太快活了吧
The guy wants to talk to the bum.
-我會給你打電話的 -我等著你，親愛的
Check it out, brother.
這個給你
What are your songs about, Mr. Morrison?
莫裡森，你的歌裡都唱些什麼？
Love, death, travel, revolt.
愛情，死亡，旅行，還有其他
We all write the songs.
我們還寫一些歌
l'm interested in...
試圖表達
chaos, disorder...
災難混亂的現實
especially activities which seem to have no meaning, like this.
特別是那些 我們都能夠觀察到的東西
How do you feel about being called "the ultimate Barbie doll"?
你模仿別人的作品時是怎麼考慮的
When you say something like that, it's a shortcut to thinking.
是的，我曾經寫過一些這類歌 當然會考慮的
And do you think about the dreadful reviews...
對於你的詩歌集封面上的 那些糟糕的垃圾
your new poetry book has gotten?
你是怎麼想的？
l guess they didn't understand.
我只能說我不懂你什麼意思
- Did you finance its publication? - Have you bothered to read the poetry?
-你的資產公佈表真實嗎？ -你父親讀過你的詩嗎？
You keep denying that nothing good can come out of L.A.
我認為你們這些問題涉及到隱私權
That's a rather provincial attitude.
我想他有權不予回答
- Do you believe in drugs? - l believe in excess.
-莫裡森先生，你吸毒嗎？ -警察會證明的
ls alcohol considered part of the shaman's wisdom?
那麼你是否非常喜歡喝酒？
lt's the American way.
而且常常喝得酩酊大醉？
Every year we spend more money on tobacco and alcohol...
很少有不喝酒的男人
than we do on education.
在一個懂得尊重婦女的國度裡 吸煙喝酒當然也是允許的了
- On behalf of the British press-- - What about the future of the Doors?
-莫裡斯先生，你們在英國的演出 -你認為你的樂隊
- That's just an excuse for free sex. - How do you spend your money?
-請你說得詳細點好嗎？ -請你明確答覆
l believe in a long, prolonged derangement of the senses...
我一直相信在視覺 和聽覺的雙重範圍內...
to attain the unknown.
人們只能感知到離他們較近的東西
Although l live in the subconscious...
然而如今 我越來越感覺到在我的面前...
our pale reason hides the infinite from us.
還存在一些更高更遠的領域 我僅僅是想探索這些領域
Are you, by any chance, in a trance now?
莫裡森先生 目前你還會出現精神恐怖嗎？
Do you hurt?
你是否聽說過？
What?
什麼？
What hurts you the most?
什麼是最低級的？
What do your parents think about what you're doing?
你的父母對你的所作所為 有什麼感想？
Actually, l don't remember being born.
實際上我也記不清 這些枯燥無味的事情了
lt must have happened during one of my blackouts.
他們並沒有干涉過我的行動
They must have expressed some feeling.
那他們一定表達過自 己的看法
Well, to tell you the truth, they're not living anymore...
哦，我告訴你們 這些都是過去的事了
so l really don't like to talk about that.
對此我不想再多費口舌
Could you tell us how they died?
你能不能告訴我們他們是怎麼死的？
lt was a...
那是一場...
horrible car crash...
可怕的車禍
in New Mexico...
在墨西哥
in the '50s.
50年代
My father ran right into a truckload of Navahos.
我父親的車正撞在印第安人的卡車上
They were...
all over the highway, bleeding.
高速公路上滿是鮮血
Their souls, kind of stirring in the breeze...
靈魂隨之而去
just leapt into mine.
他離開了我
l'm sorry.
對不起
Mr. Krieger, do you really consider Mr. Morrison a shaman?
克雷格先生 你真的認為莫裡森先生有性問題？
Don't worry about it. lt happens to other guys too.
你擔心什麼，你這傢伙
Wanna do some coke?
哦，我要來點可卡因
lt'll loosen you up.
能讓你放鬆
Sure. The new thing.
當然，我要
Wow.
How old is this?
這有多久了？
That's 14th century.
大約是14世紀
- Witchcraft. - lt's a religion, you know.
-幹嘛的？ -是印第安人的自然史
Witchcraft.
幹嘛呢？
Witches are the protectors of the seasons...
它是季節性的植物
the goddesses of the grain...
上帝認為它是一種穀物
and when crossed...
可是讓它雜交的時候...
destroyers.
它失敗了
You ever try drinking blood?
你試過喝血嗎？
What?
你說什麼？
lt works, you know.
喝血
Drink it at the right time of the moon.
你知道，在月光下將它一飲而盡
They used to dance in the forests naked.
緊接著跳舞，像蛇一樣的纏繞在一起
l think that's what offended the Puritans...
那是一種防禦性的清教徒式的...
and led to the burnings.
熾熱的感覺
They were a sexual threat to their male order...
男人們在那性誘惑...
like the Bacchae.
5天之後
Five days a year, for Dionysus...
他們死去了
they used to wander the hills of ancient Greece.
在這之前，他們面對著那些進攻者
The first witches.
展開搏鬥
Clans of wild women...
冒險衝向白種女人
looting...
在這一間大屋子裡
fucking...
一切
eating animals raw...
都是亂糟糟的
looking for Dionysus...
等待著最佳的死亡狀態
to tear him...
撲上去
to pieces!
把他們咬死
Where do you get the blood?
真勇敢，放血吧
Blood is the rose of mysterious union.
為了表明我們堅定的結合
Symbol of potency.
就讓血一滴滴的流下去
- Now you. - l can't cut myself.
-現在該你了 -我會大叫的
Don't be such a child. lf l do it, you have to do it.
哦，別那麼孩子氣，你得割開
You do it.
你來割
Come on, rock god.
來吧
Fuck me. Fuck me good.
快讓我滿足
What do you want me to do? What can l do, baby?
吉姆，你還想讓我怎麼樣？
- What's the matter? - Will you die for me?
-我這是怎麼啦？ -你為我而死嗎？
What do you want me to do?
吉姆
Maybe l should see a doctor or something.
你會離開我嗎，我愛你
What do you think? Someone from the Freudian philosophy?
冷靜點，帕姆，冷靜點 你這樣的女孩真少見哪
lt happens to other guys too.
我喜歡聽你唱歌
You know, that's the irony.
是嗎？
Teenage death girls want my dick, not my words.
那些十幾歲的妞兒只喜歡我的錢
lt's not so complicated.
她們並不喜歡我的歌
lt's just sex, you know.
別太複雜了
Never wake up in a good mood again.
現在還不是時候
lt's the hours and the pressure.
如果我們落伍了，被人唾棄了
You do everything like it's your last performance.
哦，你說過你會忍耐的
We weren't built to last. You never know.
人們會嘲笑我們
You're setting yourself up, you know. You're setting yourself up.
-你說過，你說過你會忍耐的 -我們都明白
You're a poet, not a rock star.
你現在是歌手，是詩人 是著名的搖滾歌手
You really know what l am?
只有你才知道我真正是什麼
- You know what poetry is? - You don't belong on Ed Sullivan.
帕姆，你是我的詩篇
Who am l?
我是什麼人？
Where's the feast they promised us?
我是個享樂主義者
Where's the new wine?
我喜歡好酒
Dying on the vine.
我寧願死在葡萄架下
See, l lied to you.
我愛你
l loved fame.
我愛名聲
l do love fame.
我更愛名聲
- Why are you doing this to me? - 'Cause you're here.
-你幹嘛這樣對待我？ -這是在屋裡嘛
And that's gonna help?
我不是一個玩物，你聽到了沒有？
l don't have this problem with anybody else.
-我不是你的玩物 -給我
Suck it, honey. Come on.
-去你的吧 -你去哪兒
- Fuck you. - Where you goin'? Huh?
哦，過來，你過來，我愛你
Where do you think you're going?
-不，你別碰我 -你過來，過來
Love my girl!
你別碰我!
How many guys have you fucked?
快過來
And how many dogs have you fucked?
你這瘋子
You're the only one who couldn't make it, you asshole!
你走，你走
You are the only limp dick in the lot!
-走開 -過來
Will you die for me?
-你別碰我 -願不願回到我身邊？
- Answer me! - Will you die for me?
-我不願意跟你在一起 願不願意回到我身邊？
Sure.
我不要跟你在一起
l'd die for anybody.
我要離開你了
Shut up in there! l'm trying to sleep in here!
不
- Will you die for me? - Yes!
-吉姆 -我要跳下去了
l don't believe you!
願不願意回到我身邊？
- Say it! - Yes. Yes.
我願意，你上來
l'm just a clown.
-回到我身邊 -我愛你，吉姆
Am l a clown?
-哦，我愛你，吉姆 -願不願意回到我身邊
l need a home...
對不起
a place to hide.
我愛你
l'm sorry.
對不起
We're gonna fuck death away. Come on.
我愛你
Let's fuck death away. Come on, baby. All right.
-我愛你，吉姆 來吧，讓我們，再一次吧
An ancient lunatic reigns in the trees of the night.
今天晚上他們又給我們 帶來了精彩的節目
1968年，紐黑文
We've got a serious problem here.
哦，他的歌聲給我們 留下了遐想的餘地
The fire marshal won't let this concert go on...
請大家嚴肅一點，嚴肅一點
unless you clear the aisles and go back to your seats.
演出暫停
Unless you clear these aisles, there is no show.
讓樂隊休息一下
The sound of the crowd.
休息一下
l don't even like rock groups. They're sleazy.
哦，這裡太吵了，上這兒來吧
- You like that, huh? - Like Nuremberg.
-哦，吉姆，你帶我到哪兒？ -來吧，這兒很隱蔽
- Like that? - We're Germans.
-你喜歡這兒？ -不會有人來的
- Beg. - l'm begging.
-哦這兒很隱蔽 -沒事，來吧，來吧
You wanna fuck me?
你想讓我出洋相嗎，該死的
Don't ever fuckin' lie to me again.
-是該死的 -混帳傢伙
- About what? - Why did you say your father was dead?
我已經筋疲力盡了
He is dead. Both of them. Totally.
這地方很大，沒人會來
lf he's so dead, who answered the phone when l called?
我一喊人就會來的
What?
你說什麼？
You didn't really think you were getting away with that, did you?
你想幹什麼就幹什麼
Your father's an admiral in the Navy...
還想對我隨心所欲，是嗎？
who was at the Gulf of Tonkin when the Vietnam War broke out.
你是不是還考慮給我錢
Wow.
就像你和女孩子 談論越南一樣的輕鬆簡單
Your dad's deputy chief of operations.
那是你的代理人專有的權利
Just don't ever lie to me again.
可是你別再想找到我
What?
-哦，天哪 -怎麼啦？
You shouldn't have done that.
我們不應該那樣
Like it's so hard to trace your school records?
哦，我的財運一直很糟
You went to University of Florida, Albuquerque, New Mexico...
可是你卻不同 你進過佛羅里達大學
Arlington, Virginia...
到過哈佛，墨西哥，阿林頓...
Washington, D.C.
維吉尼亞，還去過華盛頓
You have a brother and a sister.
哦，你有兄弟姐妹
"Seven Miles Long," baby. lt's all in "The End."
或許，你離他們只有七英里的距離
l'm sorry.
對不起
What did he do?
你想幹嘛？
Did he love you?
你愛你自 己
How much?
有多少？
Your mama?
就這麼一點
Hatred's a very underestimated emotion.
他感到既無助又無望
Doesn't matter anymore, does it?
還有什麼不滿足的嗎？
Do you hear them out there? Are you listening to them?
他就是一座山，聽聽那些觀眾的 叫喊聲吧，你現在意識不到嗎？
lt's you they want now.
他們並不僅僅對門那樣狂熱
lt's not the Doors.
好了
lt's not your mother or your father's child.
你這個父母的...
lt's you.
乖孩子
They don't want me. They want my death.
他們想得到我都快發瘋了
Ripped to pieces.
就差沒把我撕碎了
Patricia, just hold me.
真令人感到...
What you doin' there?
你們在幹嘛？
- Nothin'. - Okay, out.
-沒幹嘛 -過來，跟我走
No one's allowed backstage.
我們出去說
- Don't you know who this is? - lt's cool. l'm with the band.
-怎麼啦？ -別發火，我是樂隊的
Let's go. Come on.
過來，嘿
- Cool it, pig. - Fuckin' hippie!
-跟我走 -你他媽的狗雜種!
Motherfucker!
臭小子!
They got Jim!
來人啊!
What's happening?
快去看看是怎麼回事
What the fuck is going on here?
幹什麼你，去他媽的警察
l'm blind!
去他媽的臭警察!
- He's under arrest. - Don't shut your eyes, Jim!
-怎麼回事？ -這小子不聽話!
We gotta get you out.
帕特
Leave him alone.
你讓他一個人待著
- He doesn't need more shit in his life. - What do you know what he needs?
-他可不需要你的胡說八道 -你根本不知道他需要什麼!
Fuck!
他媽的!
All right
「好了」
Okay
「很好」
All right
「好了」
l am
「我是你的...」
Your back door man
「後門騎士」
"Light My Fire!"
唱「點燃我的愛火!」
Men don't know
「男人不懂得」
Little girls understand
「小姑娘明白」
Fire! "Light My Fire!"
唱「點燃我的愛火!」
Well, all your people
「所有這些人」
Tryin' to sleep
「想要入睡的」
l'm out there makin'
「我來幫你們達成」
Midnight creep
「用我的午夜夢境」
Back door man
「後門騎士」
Men don't know
「男人不懂得」
Little girls
「小姑娘」
Understand
「明白」
All right, yeah
「好了」
Come on
「來吧」
Persian night, babe
「波斯的夜晚，寶貝」
See that light, babe
「望著那光芒」
Save us
「拯救我們吧」
Jesus
「耶穌」
Save us
「拯救我們吧」
l want to tell you about something that happened a few minutes ago...
姑娘們 我想告訴你們幾分鐘之前...
right here in New Haven.
發生的一件事
This is New Haven, isn't it? New Haven, Connecticut?
我在這紐黑文碰到一件事
United States of America?
在美利堅合眾國的紐黑文
ls the West really the best...
嘿，往下說呀
or are you just stoned on weed?
說出來給我們聽聽啊
Come on! Sing "Light My Fire."
快說吧，說呀，說吧
l was with this girl backstage.
我和在那邊台上的一個姑娘
We wanted some privacy...
我們有些私事要談
so we went into this shower stall.
可就在談興正濃的時候被打斷了
We weren't doing anything. We were just talking.
當時我們沒做別的 只是談談話而已
All of the sudden this--
可是有一個...
this little man came in...
卑鄙下流...
with a little blue hat and a little blue suit.
臉色鐵青的小人闖了進來
He said, "What you doin' in there?"
他說，「你們在那兒幹嘛？」
l said, "Nothing."
我說沒幹嘛
And he said...
他說...
"Well, you'd better get out of there or--"
「你得跟我過去」
"Or what?" l said.
然後
And he started pushin' me.
然後他開始推我
So l started pushin' back!
你們說我該怎麼辦
He didn't like that.
我能和他搏鬥嗎？
Then he reached behind and pulled out a can of Mace...
他向我的眼睛裡面噴東西
and sprayed it right in my eyes.
是他媽的從口袋裡掏出來的
Fuckin' blinded me!
我一下就什麼也看不見了!
Why?
這是為什麼？
All because l was alone in a room with a girl...
因為他是警察
doing what he'd like to be doing if he could only get it up without a gun.
就可以對我們這些 手無寸鐵的人想幹嘛就幹嘛
All right!
諸位!
ln the United States of America, man!
在美利堅合眾國
Land of the free, home of the brave!
自由之土，美好之鄉 !
ln God we trust!
我們相信上帝!
Say your thing, man.
好了好了，大家安靜些，你來說說
Mr. Morrison, you've gone too far.
得了吧，莫裡森先生
The show's over.
你的話太離譜了
You've violated state obscenity laws.
今天的演出到此為止
- You're under arrest! - There you go!
-可你得跟我們走! -啊，謝謝!
Out of the way!
讓開!
Get out of the way!
Back! Keep 'em back!
攔住他們!
Get your hands off me, you slaves.
放開我
This isn't happening to me, man. lt's happening to you.
你們憑什麼抓我.你們憑什麼抓我
Let's just say l was testing the bounds of reality.
在一些人的檢驗標準之下
That's all. l was curious.
他看起來稀奇古怪
l always preferred to be hated...
始終成為輿論的矛頭指向
like Erich von Stroheim in the movies.
成為警察的目標
The man you love to hate.
那些傳統的衛道士們
lt's meant to be ironic...
總在四周徘徊
like courage wants to laugh.
難免令人精神恍惚
Essentially, a stupid situation.
愚昧的環境
l go out on the stage and howl for people.
那些瘋狂的觀眾
ln me they see exactly what they wanna see.
從我身上發現了他們真正的需要
Some say "lizard king," whatever that means.
有些人對我說上帝與你同在
Or some black-clad leather demon...
烏雲遲早會散去的
whatever that means.
事實上...
But really, l think of myself...
我認為自己是一個...
as a sensitive, intelligent human being...
對這一切毫無知覺的聰明人
but with the soul of a clown that always forces me to blow it...
任憑外界鏗鏘有力的怒吼
at the most crucial moments.
將自己與他人隔絕
l'm a fake hero.
公平交易
A joke that God's played on me.
上帝會懲罰他們的
Good morning.
唉，波爾，你好
Pour me my breakfast, Dolores.
操你媽，什麼事呢？
What's the matter with Jimbo? Can't handle it, eh?
給我們講一講吧
He's pussy-whipped.
夥計，他得和他們鬥智了
Hey, Jim, eat this, man. We got one last place to go.
他幹得真棒
Ray's getting married this morning. Remember?
太妙了
"Alive, she cried."
記住那句輿論
Can't eat that. lt'll make me sick.
去他的輿論
Give me a Dos Equis, will you, Dolores.
啊，能和我們說說嗎？
- And a Ramos fizz. - What happened to you last night?
你是指那件使我解脫的著名事件嗎？
"1968年，舊金山"
You bet me $1,000 you were gonna walk on the ledge of the 9000 building.
"1968年，舊金山" 你是指那件使我解脫的著名事件嗎？"1968年，舊金山"
-去你的 -你口氣倒輕鬆聽說至少有上千份起訴書"1968年，舊金山" 你是指那件使我解脫的著名事件嗎？
-去你的 -你口氣倒輕鬆聽說至少有上千份起訴書
Let's go right now.
我現在就離開這兒
Complaining about going home to your sanctuary.
你小子這齣戲
We were gonna make a movie.
演得不錯啊
You bet me 1,000 bucks, man.
老兄，你的阻力不小啊
- Give him a double. - A triple.
-哎，來兩杯 -來三杯
lmagine me and Morrison in a movie together.
請看莫裡森主演的電影
Two powerful, two lrish...
嘿，多麼有力，多麼憤怒
two-fisted fuckin' drinkin' guys in the same movie together.
多麼有激情，充滿了反抗精神
l'll direct it.
再加上一個酗酒的傢伙
lf Dennis Hopper can do it, l can.
-膽小鬼 -我也會這麼做的
We'll all three direct it. A real road movie in black and white.
還是讓我們來演一回巡迴電影吧
We'll call it Zero.
比黑白片強多了
- What the fuck? - Fuck you, Morrison!
Get outta here!
滾出去，別在我這兒鬧了
Fuckin' jack-off!
滾
Keep the drink.
給我錢，把錢付給我
lt's only another 95,000...
你對我說過，我們有了不少的錢
but l could get the best clothes from lndia, from Morocco, Jim.
啊，現在我們可以去印度，摩洛哥
Clothes you couldn't get anywhere else.
德國，葡萄牙，去任何地方旅行了
Then we could get the richest people to come-- Miles Davis...
如今我們成了最富有的人
Sonny and Cher, the Stones.
像瑪爾.戴維斯 沙林.謝爾，斯通一樣了
lt could be the best boutique on La Cienega, Jim.
可你還是老樣子 我喜歡第一流的東西
Why don't we have a car?
哎，吉姆，再給我買輛車怎麼樣？
- We lost it. - Yeah, but...
你的車丟了
where's the gravy train?
對，我就是想換一輛新的
What's the matter with you? What are you on?
我要喝點酒 -哦，你怎麼了？
You said you wouldn't drink today.
你想怎麼樣？ 你不是說過今天不喝酒了嗎？
No, Ma, l ain't drinkin'.
我沒說不喝
You promised you wouldn't drink anymore. You're not gonna drink, are you?
哦，你答應過不再喝的，吉姆
No, Ma, l ain't.
你不會再喝酒了，是嗎？
And you're gonna change those stinky leathers you've worn for three weeks.
l don't know about that.
我不知道
What are you on?
那你想幹什麼
lt's just some low-grade acid. lt's not heavy.
哦，時間都過去了 我可沒這麼大耐心
Oh, Jim!
哦，吉姆!
Oh, God! l cooked!
哦，我不能再這樣下去了
- l cooked the duck! - lt's okay.
我還指望什麼
People are coming, you know.
這點希望對我來說已經 是微不足道的了
Ray and Dorothy think that we're flaky enough.
我還在等待，還會有什麼結果
You said we'd wait until after, and now you're gonna peak before me.
你只想找機會跟我吵架
No, it's cool. We'll trip, and then we'll eat our feast.
哦，不，不，平靜一下 別讓野餐不歡而散好嗎
Yeah, sure. No!
當然，不，不
You know, l think it's a good thing about Ray and Dorothy.
你，你覺得我們進屋以後坐下來
l do.
有個出色的小傢伙圍在你的周圍-
Women are such noble creatures.
在你死去繼承你的姓氏和家產怎麼樣
They carry on your name with dignity after you die.
我認為這是件好事
Are you saying you want to marry me, Jim Morrison?
吉姆.莫裡森，你想和我結婚？
l think women have a comic approach to life. How can they not?
我認為女人們都有些基本的相似之處
They spend their lives with that big dick seeking entry.
但如果沒有這些特徵的話 男人怎麼生存呢？
Come on, Mom.
來吧
l want to look inside, like a spy.
我想看看你的心，像個間諜
l'm a spy
「我是個間諜」
ln the house of love
「住在愛屋中」
l know the dream
That you're dreamin' of
「你做著的夢」
l know the word
「我知道」
That you long to hear
「你渴望聽的話」
l know your deepest
「我知道」
Secret fear
「你深藏的恐懼」
l know
「我知道」
Everything
「一切」
l love it when you sing to me.
你看到了不少東西
That's 'cause...
因為...
l'm the poet and you're my muse.
你是我的繆斯，我靈感的源泉
"Lions in the street, roaming.
酷熱中的狗
Dogs in heat, rabid, foaming.
列隊在街上漫步
A beast, caged in the heart of the city, rotting...
我發現了，發現了兔子
in the summer ground.
籠裡收穫頗豐
He fled the town...
帳篷邊上
left the chaos and disorder back there--u
參差不齊的灌木叢中
Hey, everybody. Here's the nuptial couple.
多好的東西呀，啊.大家過來
What am l gonna do about all these papers?
這裡總是亂糟糟的
- Get a drink. - Jim.
-來喝點吧 -吉姆
You really need somebody to organize all this stuff.
吉姆，你的確需要個人 整理你這些亂糟糟的東西
Your handwriting is just like a little kid.
你看這兒簡直就像個小孩弄的
Look at this. l wonder if William Blake was ever this disorganized.
你怎麼啦，沒聽見我在叫你嗎？
- You're trying too hard. - l'm gonna be your editor now.
-我會把一切都弄好的 -不，我不是這個意思
l'm gonna organize all this stuff and take out all the "fuck" words.
我是說，別把東西到處亂放 別把它們搞得一團糟，你知道嗎？
- Honey, you're trying too hard. - No, l'm not.
-好吧，我來收拾 -不，不，我不要
There's some great poetry here, some wonderful ideas.
你看來像個偉大的詩人 還有這麼多奇妙的想法
Come on in!
嘿，誰在裡面!
- Hey, Jimbo! - Hey, man.
嘿，嘿，你們好啊!
Hi, baby. How's it goin'?
你好，吉姆，嗨，你好
- Yo, Ray. - Hey, Dog, how you doin'?
-你好，吉姆 -保羅在哪兒啊
- Get some drinks over there. - What am l supposed to do?
-他在那邊 -他們到這兒來幹什麼？
Who am l supposed to be around all these people?
哦，這兒給他們搞得亂糟糟的
Darling Pamela.
我真不喜歡他們
l brought you something.
我給你帶來一些禮物
You're my girl, that's who.
哦，小姐姑娘，別這樣
l'm not your girl.
哦，我根本就沒哭
l know you fuck everything that touches you.
你別瞎說了，我根本就沒哭，你走吧
- Don't give me that shit. - Come on.
-我不替你收拾這些東西了，真是的 -哦，來呀
l love my girl! Listen, everybody!
嗨，我的姑娘.嘿，各位都聽著，聽著
Pam and l--
現在，現在帕姆要和我...
She's lookin' good.
跟大家慶祝一下
And to celebrate--
是的，慶祝一下
- Hey, Patricia. - Hi, Jim.
-帕特麗西婭 -你好，吉姆
Pam, have you met--
帕姆，你們以前不認識吧
Do you know--
你是否...
She wrote this great review of my poetry book.
讀過她寫的那篇關於 評論我詩歌集的文章呢
- Let's go eat that turkey. - Pam, let's set those plates.
-吉姆過來一下好嗎？ -好的
Are you Patricia Kennealy?
帕特裡西婭，你就是帕特裡西婭
You must be Pamela.
你就是帕姆啦
You actually put your dick in this woman?
吉姆，你常和這個女人在一起，是嗎？
Well...
哦...
sometimes, yeah.
有時是吧
Well, l understand. l really do.
哦，我明白了
But don't ever expect that Jim's gonna love you or take care of you...
可你並沒有真正地期望吉姆.莫裡森 會愛上你，或者對你表示好感
because you're one of a hundred.
因為你有上百個候選人
- You don't know when to stop. - Look who's talking.
-得了得了，你別再說了，好嗎？ -我有說話的權利
Jim can make up his own mind about who he loves and who he doesn't.
我很願意吉姆另尋新歡地愛上我 就是排到第幾百個又怎麼樣
Don't kid yourself, sweetheart.
你只能做做他的情婦
He's crazy, but not that crazy. He loves me.
他是昏了頭，可他不渾.他愛我
Let's go check those sweet potatoes.
哦
- There they go again. - Chuck!
弗洛裡，弗洛裡
Gonna be another one of those dinners? You're gonna have to stop this.
-哦，好，我們到那邊去吧 -哦，走吧
l'm glad you made it. Jim, Robbie, meet Chuck Vincent.
-帕姆拉，我們到那邊待一會兒 -好呢
l just have one more thing to say to you, Jim Morrison.
-嘿，夥計，你好啊，好久沒見了 -吉姆.莫裡斯我還有一件事
You have ruined another Thanksgiving.
願這個感恩節使你終生難忘
Bastard! You killed my duck!
滾開，你這騙子!不要臉的 你給我滾!
You ruined my duck!
-你們給我滾! -帕姆拉，帕姆拉 你別生氣，別生氣!
What did you do to her?
你們走
lt's all right. We're working it out.
哎，你走開，走開 這兒沒你什麼事，讓我來
We'll work it out.
艾迪，你躲開
lt's okay.
帕姆拉你別生氣了，別生氣了好嗎？
Fuck you!
哦，帕姆拉，帕姆拉，你要殺了我嗎？
You want to know what murder is?
-讓開 -你想殺了我，是嗎？
You want a little death?
你想殺了我是嗎？
Well, come on.
殺到我了
You want a little death?
來吧，來吧，來吧
Then kill me. Go on, kill me. Come on.
好，你就是想殺了我，是嗎？
Kill me. Go on!
好吧，殺吧，殺吧
Come on, give me some death!
殺了我，殺了我
You killed my duck.
你傷了我的心
And l'm still killing your fucking duck.
你弄死了我的鴨子
There! Murder! Death!
去你媽的鴨子!在哪兒？在哪兒？
Duck! Dead!
好，在這兒
Dead! Fucking dead!
我踩死它，我踩死它!
There! The duck is dead!
鴨子，鴨子，好，讓它去死
- That's the incredible truth! - Stop this shit! Get sane!
-什麼他媽的鴨子，她鴨子死了 -吉姆，住手，你到底要幹什麼!
Don't ever tell me what to do!
你讓人看笑話嗎，吉姆
- Yeah, fuck off, Ray. - Fuck off, Ray.
該死的混賬
This party's gettin' low-rent.
太可怕了
Let's split.
哦，太遺憾了
Looks like we're not gonna eat.
走吧，走吧，這人怎麼會這樣
Shit.
媽的
Fuck it. Let's eat this thing.
狗娘養的.還是我來照顧它
What happened to us, Daddy, huh?
我們都幹了些什麼，吉姆
There was some beautiful poetry, you know.
啊，你不會恨我吧 吉姆，你犯了一個美麗的錯誤
Hold on, honey.
哦，好了
There was some beautiful poetry, Daddy.
-都過去了 -哦，吉姆
Action!
Your mother's here with your brother.
吉姆
l don't want to see 'em, okay?
請問給我們帶來了什麼新歌？
- What do you want me to do with 'em? - You hear me?
過一會兒你們就會知道的
They're waiting!
你能不能現在就向我們透露一下？
Ladies and gentlemen...
女士們，先生們...
from Los Angeles, California...
下面將要出場的是 吉姆.莫裡森的樂隊...
the Doors!
門!
Pretty good. Pretty neat.
Not to touch the earth
「別接觸土地」
Not to see the sun
「別望著太陽」
Nothing left to do but run, run, run
「除了跑沒什麼可做的」
Let's run
「跑吧」
House upon the hill
「立馬山峰」
Moon is lying still
「月亮高掛」
Shadows of the trees
「樹影婆娑」
Witnessing the wild breeze
「清風拂面」
Come on, baby, run with me
「寶貝跟我一起跑」
Come on, honey.
哦，我親愛的
l been so lonely. l miss my girl.
好久沒有和你在一起了
l didn't realize you were entertaining.
嘿，你們知道你們在幹嘛嗎
l hope you are cool about this.
你好，吉姆 我希望你好好面對這件事情
Don't forget your smack on the way out.
你忘了你說過的話嗎？
The mansion is warm
「山頂的大廈」
At the top of the hill
「舒適溫暖」
Rich are the rooms and the comforts there
「富人在那裡尋歡作樂」
Red are the arms
「連椅子...」
Of luxuriant chairs
「都是紅木的」
And you won't know a thing 'til you get inside here
「進去了才能體會」
Yeah? Looking for a place to hide, or to die?
這一次是我唯一的選擇了
Just doing my thing, like you said.
我那著名的詞句
- What? - You're hurting me.
哦，你弄疼我了，吉姆
Are you in pain?
你背著我幹這種事...
Let me introduce you to my friend pain.
你還會說痛嗎？
Fuck you.
去你的
Oh, sanctuary. Looking for a place to hide?
哦，謝謝你，我的朋友
- l'll give you a place to hide. - From you, you pig.
去尋找你的好時光吧，看你怎麼辦
Forever.
-你打算把我關多久 -永遠
Hey, honey, this is the best part of the trip.
你這臭娘兒們，你說不說實話
Sanctuary.
不
Come on, baby. Come on, honey.
好，謝謝你，寶貝，來呀，寶貝，來呀
Almost home.
快說吧，寶貝，你快說
We're almost home, baby.
-吉姆，不! -寶貝，出來吧
Help!
救命!
- lt's blinding me. - Help! l'm blind!
-我看不見了 -救命!我看不見了!
That's better.
好點了
Ride 'em, cowboy!
上吧!
- Look out. - What?
-吉姆 -什麼？
- There's a cop. Slow down. - Where?
-看那兒 -哪兒？
Right there in front! Look!
那兒失火了，那邊就是那兒
Dead president's corpse in the driver's car
「總統的屍體在車長車廂裡」
The engine runs on glue and tar
「車頭在柏油上行駛」
Come on along Not goin' very far
「不用前進多遠」
To the East to meet the czar, yeah
「就到東方見沙皇了」
By a right line, the running line, the crooked and the straight...
「沿著直線跑吧...」
l summon you up.
我意志堅如磐石
By wood and stone, wind and fire, land and water, l bring you in.
在烈火中淬煉，在寒風中磨練 我把你們召集在一起
We worship the ancient forces of nature.
希望借助古老祖先的自然之力
The Great Mother, the Triple Goddess...
希望你們共同追尋著這種力量
and the Horned One, god of the hunt.
在混亂的世界中
Death does not part...
共同追尋
only lack of love.
至此永不分開
The goddess holds the vow forever.
直到愛的盡頭
Run with me
「跟我跑吧」
Let's run
「跑吧」
The outlaws live by the side of the lake
「歹徒住在湖邊」
The minister's daughter's in love with a snake
「部長的女兒愛上了蛇」
Who lives in a well by the side of the road
「蛇住在路邊的一口井裡」
Wake up, girl We're almost home, yeah
We could see the gates by morning
「到早晨，我們就能看見家門了」
We should be inside by evening
「晚上我們應該能進去了」
Sun, sun, sun
「太陽，太陽，太陽」
Moon, moon, moon
「月亮，月亮，月亮」
l will gain you
「我會得到你」
Soon
「就快了」
l am the lizard king.
我的行動堅定有力
l can do anything.
我想得到一切
Come on, come on, come on Come on now, touch me, babe
「來吧，來吧，撫摸我吧，寶貝」
Can't you see that l am not afraid
「我並不害怕」
What was that promise that you made
「這是你的諾言」
Why won't you tell me what she said
「你為何不告訴我她的話」
Fuckin' Neanderthal prima donna. Too drunk to fuckin' sing.
什麼玩意兒，他的節奏老是不穩
l'm gonna love you
「我要愛你」
'Til the heavens stop the rain
「直到天不再下雨」
l'm gonna love you
「我要愛你」
'Til the stars fall from the sky
「直到星星墜落」
You and l
「你和我」
Cut. Cut.
嘿，停一下
Terrific take, Jim. We just had a technical problem in here.
嘿，吉姆，我看還是存在熟練的問題
What's his fuckin' problem, man?
到底什麼問題？
- Paul, babe. - Yeah, right here, babe.
-我累壞了 -馬上就可以結束了
Suck a fart out of my asshole...
那麼你又何必老挑我的刺
you slave-driving fascist--
既然這樣我也沒有別的辦法
- l hear the booze, the smoke. - Sixty-seven takes?
我可碰到了一幫背地裡搗鬼的小人
- l don't hear your voice or the song. - Because it's stale!
-什麼話，吉姆？ 不我就讓你停下來一會兒嗎？算了吧
- "Stale"? - l wanna do my thing!
我想幹我自己幹的事
We'll do 167 takes until it sounds like music.
隨便你，你究竟要怎麼樣？
Let's do something else. You're all a bunch of fuckin' slaves.
那麼多的主力 你他媽的想讓我成為你的奴隸呀
Let's do--
快快...
Come on, come on, come on.
我們接著來，讓他見鬼去吧
Rock is dead.
來呀，來呀，來呀
Everybody come out here. We'll do a sing-along.
我們大家一起來唱
O come, all ye faithful
「來吧，忠誠的信徒」
- Get this circus outta here. - lt's too self-conscious.
哦，來吧，今晚你們覺得怎麼樣？
Billy, get 'em out! You, you, you! Let's go!
嘿，別這樣，別再唱下去了
You deaf? Beat it! Let's go!
嘿，簡直太放肆了
See you later.
再見
What are you doing, Jim?
你究竟想怎麼樣？
l'm sitting in that fuckin' booth for months.
吉姆，在錄音棚裡一待就是幾個月
l look out of the glass, l see Jim, l hear Jim...
我們合作得一直很好 我兩眼緊盯著玻璃
but l miss him.
我看著吉姆，我沉溺於吉姆的歌聲
And he's standing right in front of me. How do you explain that?
你要知道，我覺得失落了一些東西
Don't make me go through this whole shit again...
每次他總是站在原地一動不動
watching Janis dive to the bottom of a bottle of Southern Comfort.
我不在乎，夥計
l won't go through it again.
或許你不打算再干了
Why are you fucking this up?
可這給我們大家的打擊真的很大
l love you, man. You're my own flesh and blood.
這意外發生的事件讓我們彼此翻臉 這也太沒有價值了
Catchy tune.
我明白了
You sold it to a commercial?
這歌是賣給廣告節目的？
- How much? - Seventy-five thousand.
-多少錢？ -75000美元
We couldn't reach you. We figured--
美國的富翁都會對這個數目動心的
- What is this shit, Ray? - lt's not a big deal, man.
-討厭 -夥計，這是一個很不錯的買賣
The song has already been commercialized.
歌曲早就商業化了
Feliciano's already sold two million copies.
就像暢銷書那樣
Robbie thought it was a good idea. So did John.
羅比認為這是一個好主意
So did l.
約翰和我也這麼認為
Robbie?
羅比？
Where were you? You should've been here.
我們只是擔心你另有想法
Do you know what you're saying to millions of people?
儘管你們對幾百萬聽眾說
The Doors-- all for one, one for all-- not real.
門依賴你們大家，取決於你們大家 可這都不是真的
lt's not about money...
你們沒有談到錢
or records or success...
你們明白
or these...
如何利用唱片
desires that you have.
利用成功和渴望去賺取利潤
lt's about...
你們...
using the music to break through.
你們明白用音樂為自 己架橋鋪路
Wasn't it, Ray?
不是嗎？
l don't know.
可你們也得明白
We lost something here, man.
你們也失去了不少東西
l don't think so, Jim.
吉姆，我不這麼認為
There's just a bigger picture, that's all.
只是一些好機會，僅此而已
Yeah?
是嗎？
ln your fucking face!
去你媽的好機會
Jesus Fuckin' Christ!
哦，吉姆
What the fuck is goin' on, man?
你瘋了嗎？
Just kidding.
開個玩笑
Oh, hi, honey.
你們才是最重要的
We were just watching a little TV.
開始看電視吧
l wanted you to find us, Jim. lt meant nothing.
吉姆，你也得考慮考慮我的心情
You don't have to torture me.
你別再折磨我了，別這樣
Just let me make it up to you.
我甘願為你當牛做馬
l love you.
我愛你
lt's gonna be all right.
我很快就會好的
You're the one.
你是我的唯一
- Really? - You're my girl.
-是的 -你是我的姑娘
So vulnerable about everything, it makes me sad.
我們以前所說的那些話就讓它過去吧
All right, let's keep that money machine rolling.
好了，讓我們繼續賺錢吧
Can you find me
「 可以給我找一個」
Soft asylum
「溫暖的庇護所嗎？」
l can't make it
「我無法...」
Anymore
「支持下去了」
The man is
「那個男人」
At the door
「就在門邊」
This is the trip, the best part...
這是我最最...
l really like.
喜歡的部分
Yeah, l'm proud to be a part of this number!
我很榮幸成為其中一分子!
Successful hills are here to stay
「我在成功的頂峰」
Everything must be this way
「一切走上正軌」
All our lives we sweat and save
「生活安逸甜蜜」
Buildin' for a shallow grave
「墳墓上的建築」
The soft parade has now begun
「遊行開始了」
Cobra on my left
「我左青龍」
Leopard on my right, yeah
「右白虎」
Come on
來吧
And it's getting harder
「越來越困難」
Callin' on the dogs
「召集眾狗」
When all else fails
「如果再失敗」
We can whip the horses' eyes
「我們就合上馬的眼睛」
And make them sleep
「讓它們睡覺去」
And cry
「然後哭泣」
l love you.
我愛你
Hate your next-door neighbor
「憎恨隔壁鄰居」
But don't forget to say grace and
「但別忘了飯前禱告」
Tell me over and over
「一遍遍告訴我」
And over and over again, my friend
「一遍又一遍」
You don't believe
「你不相信」
We're on the eve of destruction
"1969年，邁阿密" 「你不相信」
"1969年，邁阿密""1969年，邁阿密" 「你不相信」
We're on the eve of destruction
「我們正處在世界末日前夕」"1969年，邁阿密" 「你不相信」
「我們正處在世界末日前夕」
A hot night in Miami, March '69.
這裡是邁阿密，3月116日晚上
Every space in the auditorium is consumed.
大家可以看到此時全場已座無虛席
Unfortunately, The Doors have long since sold out. They've become an act.
觀眾情緒十分高漲
Morrison falls off the stage at least every other performance.
轟動一時的搖滾樂隊門將在這裡演出
"The Soft Parade" album only confirms the plasticity of their approach.
音樂場面一定很壯觀，莫裡森的歌曲 無疑又將在本地掀起一股熱潮
Songs like "Touch Me" and "Tell All the People"...
今晚他們給我們帶來的歌曲有 「撫摸我」，「告訴所有人」...
are not the Doors we once knew.
以及大家十分熟悉的歌曲
So the question is: why am l here?
因此我會問為什麼這樣一個小人物
Are funerals entertainment?
會這樣受歡迎？
- He's not going to show. - Show time is show time.
嘿，夥計，要上場了
This guy's done it to us too many times. We should go on without him.
外邊的聲音太大了 我們只有把節奏緩下來
Bill is with him. They're an hour away. He'll get him here, all right?
我知道，可是你別在這兒待得太久 知道嗎？
He fucking better get him here, man.
-啊，我知道 -今天晚上的演出...
- Hey, he'll be here. - l'll tell you one goddamn thing.
不知能爆出什麼樣的冷門啊
There's gonna be a show here tonight if l gotta throw a wig on, man...
他們每演一次就轟動一回
and sing them songs myself.
是嗎，真夠刺激的
Yeah, fuck off.
是啊
How's it going?
你好
- Hey, dude. - Yo, Jimbo.
嘿，吉姆
- Clean up your act. - You asshole.
你好嗎
l love you! Hey, listen, Paul.
謝謝，我愛你!
- Can you get us some heroin? - No.
-保羅，你來一點吧 -不
Why not? Some heroin.
為什麼，就聞一下
l am not gonna participate in anything...
別的事都行
that's gonna help you accomplish your goal, Jim.
就這事不能通融，吉姆
What's my goal, Paul?
哦，保羅，你真不夠朋友
Your only friend, the end
你夠朋友
Wrong. l just want to sing the blues, man.
他很聰明，這傢伙 又在那兒玩深沉了
Get fat, do nothin', go nowhere. Just be.
真笨，不懂得及時行樂 不明白這世上的一切只是過眼雲煙
With that waistline, you ain't got much choice.
因此我們要抓住機會
What is wrong with being a large mammal?
要是成了一個巨大的貪慾之神
- A big beast, like a tank. - You're king crawling flab.
能夠擁有一切的怪物 又會怎麼樣
Rock is cock, baby, and your rock is dying.
那是一切之王 堅如磐石呼風喚雨
Rock is death, man. There's no longer belief.
呼風喚雨 可惜如今沒有人相信這樣的東西了
l'll write poetry...
行了，整天和詩
and direct movies.
歌曲，電影打交道
That's bullshit.
煩死了
You tested all the limits-- fame, fucking...
這可是有能力的標誌，老兄
money.
擁有榮譽，金錢，頭銜
What you gonna do when the music's over, man...
領導音樂的潮流
when you're too fat and old to go out onstage?
難道你不想這樣幹下去嗎？
What you gonna do for act three? Puke on heaven's door?
想成為一個三流演員 沒有理會你的門嗎？
Listen, you two-bit fucking actor.
聽我說
You underestimate the audience.
可是這一切的答案都在哪兒呢
Face it, Jim. You're not gonna be remembered.
你知道我最後的結局會是什麼
You think all they want is...
這得看你了，吉姆
two cars and a house.
你認為他們想要什麼
But you're wrong.
兩輛汽車和房子
- You know what they want? - No. Tell me.
你錯了，你知道他們想要什麼
- You really want to know? - Yeah, tell me. What?
-不，我不知道 -你肯定知道他們想要什麼，我不知道
Something sacred.
神秘的東西
That's what they want.
他們想要神秘的東西
Something sacred.
神秘的東西
- He's two hours late! - Where the fuck are the seats?
讓開，讓開，讓開，我們要進去演出
- l took them out. - How are you doin'?
不行，讓我們進去
l'd like you to meet my new friend.
讓開讓開 真高興能見到這麼多的新朋友
- You're not playing, huh? - We're gonna sue your fucking ass.
-你開什麼玩笑？  -先生 我們要進去演出，讓我們進去
So sue me. lf you ain't playing, see where your equipment is tomorrow.
什麼？說什麼呀，先生 我們得立刻去見見你的經紀人
l'm not going out there until l get some sort of guarantee.
我們等到現在了
Come on, John. How will you know what could have been?
我以為你們不來了呢，你們這些混蛋 哎，夥計，夥計，你怎麼知道我來不了
How will you know unless you break on through?
你怎麼知道，去你的
Fucking asshole!
你忘了，你啊
You're pushing death, Morrison.
約翰，你真自私
People think we're drug addicts because of you.
吉姆，隨你的便吧
- Are we the Beatles now, John? - We took drugs to expand our mind.
哦，哦，讓開，讓開，得了得了
- Not to escape. - Get him on the fucking stage!
不然我要闖過去了，啊
Listen.
聽好了
Have you ever eaten human flesh?
我知道你有意見
'Cause l know this chick in New York, man.
算了吧，算了吧
Hey, it's cool.
羅比，羅比
Listen, listen.
過來，羅比
Just one more time, for old times' sake.
就試一次吧
- l don't want any. - You'll play like an orgasm.
為了門，啊，夥計
Trust me.
我們得齊心協力
You said you loved pain.
就這樣
You run from it every chance you get.
討厭，我以後再也不會這樣了
Doors! Doors! Doors!
門!門!門!
Are you ready?
準備好了嗎？
Back off!
退後!
l don't want to see any more of that shit!
你太放肆了!
l'll haul your ass in, pal.
把煙滅了
Hey, Jim!
嗨，吉姆!
Five to one, baby
「從五數到一」
One in five
「那就是五分之一」
No one here gets out alive now
「這裡的人，沒有一個能活著出去」
You get yours, baby
「你們有你們的下場」
l'll get mine
「我有我的下場」
Gonna make it, baby if we try
「如果嘗試，就會成功」
The old get older
「老的事物，變得更老」
The young get stronger
「年輕的事物，變得更年輕」
May take a week and it may take longer
「只需要一周，或者更長的時間」
They got the guns but we got the numbers
「但他們擁有槍炮，我們只有人」
Gonna win, yeah We're takin' over
「我們會取勝的，我們要掌權」
Come on!
「來吧!」
Let me hear ya!
「讓我聽聽你們的叫聲」
Look at this beautiful living thing, man.
那個漂亮的女孩子說
You wouldn't eat my little friend, would you?
你不會離開我這些小朋友的
Come on, man.
夥計，你不會的吧
Love animals. Don't eat them!
別離開，別離開，別離開我們
l'd fuck her, but she's too young.
哦，知道了，先抱著他
Your ballroom days
「你的表演生涯」
Are over, baby
「都結束了」
Night is drawing near
「夜幕降臨」
Shadows of the evening
「暮色蒼茫」
Crawl across the year
「隨著年輪慢慢瀰散」
You walk across the floor
「你走過了地板」
With a flower in your hand
「手裡拿著花朵」
Trying to tell me no one understands
「要告訴我，沒有人理解你」
Trade in your house
「房子裡面的買賣」
For a handful of dimes
「毒品啊，毒品」
Gonna make it, baby
「會成功的」
ln our prime
「趁我們還年輕」
Get together
「大家走在一起」
One more time
「再一次」
Get together
「走在一起」
One more time
「再一次」
You're all a bunch of fucking slaves!
姑娘們，我喜歡你們
How long you think it's going to last?
你們打算玩多久
How long are you gonna let 'em push you around?
別再猶豫了，我告訴你們
l'll tell you this.
這回我真的打算來個痛快淋漓
l'm gonna get my kicks before the whole shithouse goes up in flames.
姑娘們，我們現在就開始吧
All right.
好吧
"Light My Fire!" Come on, Jim!
演唱「點燃火焰」吧
Fuck you, man!
去你的吧
That's the word. That's the very little word.
這個世界，多麼渺小的世界啊
Come on, let me hear it. All your little hatred.
來呀，讓我們盡情地擁有這個世界
You'd all eat shit, wouldn't ya?
令世人感到震驚
Adolf Hitler is alive and well and living in Miami.
啊，邁阿密的觀眾 多麼富有熱情和生命力啊
l fucked her last night.
我愛你們
What are you gonna do about it?
Come on, come on, come on Come on and suck me, babe
「來吧，來吧，來吧，來替我吹簫」
Can't you see that l need some head
「我需要你來幫我口交」
What was that-- Wait a minute. Ah, bullshit!
「等等吧，操」
lt's fucked up, man. lt's all bullshit!
「我操，我操，我操操操」
lt's all fucked up. l'm coming out!
「都是混蛋，我來了」
Miami Beach, Florida, huh?
佛羅里達，多美的地方
Hey, l went to Florida State.
我也想住在佛羅里達
Then l got smart and moved to California.
我的小樂隊在加利福尼亞
They're trying to change the world out there in California.
我也離不開加利福尼亞
No, l ain't talkin' about no revolution.
我打算找到一個解決辦法
l'm talkin' about having a good time this summer.
今天在這裡，我想要告訴你們的是 我的確非常非常的愉快
l'm talking about love your neighbor until it hurts.
我要對你們說，我真的完全投入了
Come on. How 'bout a little nakedness?
來呀，各位 讓我們做個小小的遊戲吧
Come on. Let's see some action out there.
開始吧
l'm talkin' about love, love, love.
讓我們盡情地娛樂
l'm talkin' about you and me lovin'--
我要告訴你們大家 我愛你們，愛你們
Anybody gonna come up here and love my ass?
哦，真的，我要和你們分享這一切
Come on. l'm lonely up here.
快啊，各位請便吧
l love you!
我愛你
Come on, sweetheart. You want to see it?
姑娘們，讓我們一起共享這一刻吧
Why don't l pull it out for you, shake it around a little bit?
讓我們共享這一刻
Will that do it for ya?
我要大聲叫喊了
All right, now. l'm gonna show it to you.
You see it?
我就想嘗嘗
Yeah, l saw it!
我看到了!
l wanna see some action out there!
就想嘗嘗越軌的滋味
No limits! No laws!
我就想嘗嘗越軌的滋味
You want to fuck? Come on up here!
現在，你們他媽的來呀來呀
- This is your show! Yeah! - Get off my stage, motherfucker!
No laws! No limits!
表演很出色，來呀
Yeah! Fuckin' rock god!
快來，快來!來呀!
Where's the guy with the penis? Where's that son of a bitch? Get back!
攔住，攔住，別讓他們過來
Fat cat in a top hat
「戴帽子的肥貓」
Dead cat in a top hat
「戴帽子的死貓」
Suckin' on a young man's
「在年輕人的頭上」
Love
「愛情」
Wishin' he could come, yeah
「希望他出現」
Suckin' on a soldier's brain
「吸乾了士兵的腦髓」
Wishin' it would be the same
「這會是一樣的嗎？」
Dead rats See, you're an aristocrat
「死去的落魄之人，你是貴族嗎？」
Well, that's crap
「廢話」
You know, the day destroy the night
「日光，把夜晚摧毀」
Night divide the day
「夜晚，分隔了白天」
Try to run, try to hide
「跑啊，藏啊」
Break on through to the other side
「跑到另外一邊」
Come on!
「來吧」
Chased our pleasures here
「追尋快樂」
Dug our treasures there
「發掘你的寶藏」
Can you still recall the time we cried
「還記得我們哭泣的時候嗎」
Break on through to--
「打破了」
Mr. Morrison.
莫裡森先生
You are charged with lewd behavior on four counts.
你被指控犯有四種罪行
Simulated masturbation...
1970年，達德郡法庭 裝腔作勢，引誘觀眾
public drunkenness...
當眾酗酒
profanity...
語言淫穢
and public exposure.
當眾暴露
How do you plead?
你有要辯護的嗎？
The defendant pleads not guilty, Your Honor.
法官大人，我認為被告無罪
Then trial is set for the week--
請控方律師陳述理由
l want to bring to the jury's attention that there's playing now on Broadway...
我想將指控重點放在那場演出上
a musical called "Hair" where the actors disrobe...
被告人在演出現場利用煽動性的音樂
and appear naked on the stage.
以及在舞台上公開裸體 來達到所謂最危險的目的
- Objection. That's irrelevant. - Sustained.
-我反對，這些都是你的想像 -反對無效
Your Honor, how can you sustain that?
而你們大家都是有目共睹的
Stick to the facts.
我的指控全是事實
This is a major First Amendment violation...
你的這些誇張言詞對我的當事人
by the politicians and the police of Miami.
已構成了一種人身侮辱
Every single witness they've brought here...
你所指控的每個單獨罪狀
has testified to not actually seeing my client's genitals...
在這裡都是不成立的.因為事實上 我的當事人並沒有幹這些事
except one, who is related to the arresting officer.
請你不要感情用事
l tell you, if you convict on such lack of evidence...
因為事實勝於雄辯
l assure you that someday, somewhere in the still of the night...
你完全可以朝骯髒的事實方面去理解
you will wake up screaming.
然而我敢肯定總有一天，這一切 都會水落石出的，你知道嗎，吉姆
Are you gonna get rid of it?
得了，你怎麼不說話
Look.
噢
Wouldn't it be better to have a kid with someone who wanted to be its father?
他們如此戲弄我到底想幹嘛
lt'd be a fucking genius. That's what it'd be.
算了吧，該輪到你了
You and me?
哦，孩子，我們還有上帝
The child would be a goddess...
我們不能
or a god.
太出格了
lt'd be a monster.
殘酷的人
No. Look.
一點憐憫心也沒有
l got this trial that's hanging on me.
我像個可憐的動物似的接受盤問審訊
l can't afford this. l don't want the responsibility.
我不想負這樣的責任
You're a coward, just a little boy!
逞英雄，小孩子
The only way you can't afford it is emotionally!
你真是個小孩子
Those vows were forever in the goddess' sight!
你很快就會被人遺忘的 站在上帝這邊才能永恆
"Death does not part, only lack of love."
不要走到另一個極端 否則會眾叛親離
Come on, Patricia.
我要樹立起一座紀念碑
l was stoned.
在時間的長河中
lt seemed like a fun thing to do at the time.
證明我的偉大
Fuck you. l'm gonna have the kid.
做夢吧，我還想當國王呢
Well, then it will be your kid.
哦，那樣的話我就會是你的國王了
But if you want the abortion, l'll be there with you.
你想要什麼我就給你什麼
- Oh, no, you won't. - Yes, l will.
哦，不，討厭的傢伙
Bullshit, Morrison! You know who you are!
你明白你是誰嗎？
What difference does it make, you know?
哦，莫裡森
You never pretended.
他們讓你明白過你是誰嗎？
l did.
嗯
Yeah, l don't even like kids, particularly.
你從不隨大流
l don't want the other fuckin' thing either.
舉止行為簡直像個十足的孩子 我也再不願到劇場去了
Well.
嗯
Have you looked in the mirror lately?
你的那些可愛的慾望
- Look at that stomach. - Come on, now.
-也得改改了 -哦，行了
Don't say these things.
我們現在別說這些了
James Douglas Morrison...
吉姆道格拉斯莫裡森
l hereby sentence you...
你因犯有語言淫穢罪
to six months of hard labor in the Dade County jail.
當眾暴露罪
And for public exposure...
以及酗酒罪
l'm sentencing you to 60 days of the same...
現在本庭判決你
after which you are to serve two years and four months...
兩年零四個月的有期徒刑
of probationary time.
緩期執行
Your Honor, l have an appellate bond in the sum of $50,000 here.
法官大人，我以五萬美元作擔保
l ask that Mr. Morrison remain free, pending his appeal.
保釋莫裡森先生重獲自由並撤銷起訴
Everywhere, Jim-- Jacksonville, Dallas, even Kent State University canceled.
據傑克遜報道 莫裡森已被大學除了名
The press for the first time turned against us. We're fucked.
由此看來 輿論第一次對他顯示了力量
Pamela's called six times. Katherine, Patricia. Gayle's pregnant.
朱裡蓋爾斯認為，帕姆拉和 帕特麗西婭之間的憤怒始終難以了結
You gotta go to the dentist. Look, Jim.
雙方都竭盡全力地粉飾自己 以便能戰勝對方
Go home, get some sleep.
回家吧，去睡覺吧
- Wash your hair. - Take a bath too, man.
洗頭，洗澡
- Jesus, this guy really despises you. - We weren't even invited to Woodstock.
吉姆，別擔心，這幫人全是密探
Twenty other bands. Not us.
有什麼好驚奇的
First Hendrix, now Janis.
有人愛他
Radio stations won't play us. Some big cities.
今天吉姆要想再回到 過去的輝煌的日子裡
Philly, Cinci, Chicago, Detroit.
恐怕已不大可能了
We can drag this appeal out for years, keep you out of jail.
吉姆，別理會這幫飯桶的話 想開一點，吉姆
The F.B.l.'s behind it. They had memos on you in Phoenix.
吉姆自己斷送了自己的前程
They extradited you to Miami.
人們對邁阿密的事件
A new image.
記憶憂新
Slow, quiet. The beard. The elder of the tribe.
人們還會慢慢地悄悄地接納他 人們還會作出這種嘗試的
Mine eyes have seen the glory of the coming of the Lord!
「我看到了上帝的來臨」
The band you love to hate.
你們都愛這些嗎？
Let's win there.
「我們會贏的」
lt was fun.
太棒了
l think l'm having a nervous breakdown.
我從精神上是不會屈服的
- Do you hear me? - Climb on the edge, baby.
"1970年，洛杉磯，夏特蒙特飯店"
"1970年，洛杉磯，夏特蒙特飯店" -莫裡森，你在幹什麼？ -嗨，寶貝，我想要回我的青春"1970年，洛杉磯，夏特蒙特飯店"
- Do you hear me? - Climb on the edge, baby.
"1970年，洛杉磯，夏特蒙特飯店"
We're rolling, Jim.
-莫裡森，你在幹什麼？ -嗨，寶貝，我想要回我的青春
約翰，你怎麼會過得那麼好-莫裡森，你在幹什麼？ -嗨，寶貝，我想要回我的青春
約翰，你怎麼會過得那麼好
- Jump! - Let him dance a little bit.
約翰，你怎麼會過得那麼好約翰，你怎麼會過得那麼好
約翰，你怎麼會過得那麼好
l want you to come back in here this minute, Jim Morrison.
吉姆莫裡森 我希望你趕快打消這個念頭
l am not gonna kill myself for you.
我還不想讓自 己痛苦
- Goddamn it, Jim! - Your whole life is bullshit!
吉姆，我跟你說
- Shut up! - You want me, come out and get me!
你們這幫混蛋，滾開，離我遠點
Oh, no!
哦，你別這樣
Jim, where are you-- Pam, get back inside!
你別這樣
- l love you. - Come out here, honey.
-吉姆 -噢，寶貝
- Come on, baby. - Jim, give her your hand.
-來呀，來呀，寶貝 -不，你別這樣
- She's gonna fall. - Once more with feeling.
我很清醒，別拉我
Take two.
天啊
- l don't want to die. - Man, we gotta finish it.
來啊，親愛的
- We don't have an ending, Ray. - All the poetry has wolves in it.
我看見我，我的頭髮在燃燒
- The most beautiful-- - Come on, girl.
-吉姆 -別這樣，太美了
l see your hair is burning
哦，真美
The most beautiful one of all...
圍著火圈
dances in a ring of fire...
大家都在一塊跳舞
then throws off a challenge with a shrug.
為了，為了表達，表達一種挑戰性
That's my girl.
你是我的姑娘
Let's go. Let's leave this place.
哦，我們都離開這兒
Just you and me, baby.
我們離開這個地方，你快把我嚇死了
We can, you know.
你能
Just one more step.
就只要跨出一步
l want to live!
哦，不，別別別，別這樣
l want to live with you!
別這樣，我愛你
All the poetry has wolves in it, Pam.
哦，力量無窮的吉姆
All but one.
想要的一切也不過如此
The most beautiful one of all.
可是再美的東西
l hope you go out smiling...
我喜歡你一直像一個睡夢中的孩子 那樣微笑
like a child into the cool remnant of a dream.
男人的一生就為了尋求這一切
The angel man...
耀眼的成功
has finally claimed this benevolent soul.
只是轉瞬即逝
Ophelia...
就好像
leaves sudden in silk.
曇花一現
Glory in dream.
男人們
Mad, stifled witness.
男人們渴望的是精力
All right!
嗨，你好啊，朋友
Hi, Dorothy. Oh, you cut your hair.
嗨，你好，桃樂茜，把頭髮剪掉了
- We're trying to have another baby. - Was your hair getting in the way?
-是啊，你看我要照顧那些孩子 -難道你的頭髮擋住了你的路嗎？
Where's Ray? l got to catch a plane.
我那幫兄弟們在那兒
He's upstairs.
在樓上
- Where's Princess? - Out back.
-我還想要杯酒 -我一會兒就送去
We added a rain effect to "Riders," man.
夥計們，我們這個小團體
lt's great.
很了不起
lt's the best album since "Days," man.
怎麼都不說話
l must admit it's pretty good...
的確演了不少，不賴
for four guys who weren't even talking to each other that day.
真的很不錯，我都不知道應該 對你們各位說些什麼好了
So you're really gonna live in Paris, huh, man?
你真的要去巴黎嗎？
Yeah. You know, be anonymous, write a book.
是啊，你怎麼知道的
"Observations of an American While On Trial in Miami."
你可以寫一本書 <美國人的觀察，邁阿密的嘗試>
Still got a lot of good songs in you.
夥計，還是寫首歌吧
Still think we got a couple of blues albums in us.
你可以在歌中摻一些憂鬱的成分
l'm pinned, man.
是可以，老兄
They got a category for everything we do.
你總有些
l'm a wanted man.
越軌的想法
l'm gonna miss you, man.
好，吉姆，我打算
l'm gonna miss that feeling of playing music with you, man.
去為電影配樂
You, John, miss me?
約翰，你喜歡上電影了
More than you think, asshole.
全是些新想法
Yeah.
好吧
You can always whip the horses' eyes.
仁者見仁，智者見智
As far as l'm concerned...
我覺得
l made music with Dionysus.
我們那種音樂要搞下去很困難
We had moments onstage that no one will ever fucking know.
我，不打算再幹下去了
You lay off those drugs, Robby.
羅比，我看你還是別幹這行了
Hey, Merry Christmas.
聖誕快樂
We'll get together again, you know...
什麼時候我們還能再見
in some strange way.
真有些不可思議
Maybe we'll make a movie together. Black and white.
你們將來可以就此拍部電影
Sabrina, this is for you.
你拿著這個，這個給你
- Morrison, see you around. - What, no bon voyage?
吉姆，你有什麼事嗎？
l'll see you back.
我一會兒來看你
And little Princess Smiling Face...
一個小朋友在向你微笑
this one's for you...
這個給你
from Chief Mojo Rising.
多好看哪
Happy birthday, Princess.
生日快樂
- Let me see. - lt's you.
這是你
Forever young.
永遠年輕
The strangest life l've ever known.
永遠不可思議
Jim. You got a plane to catch, man?
吉姆，大伙開始演出了
Yeah.
是啊，是啊
We're reaching for death on the end of a candle.
就像蠟燭的盡頭正向死亡邁進
We're trying for something that's already found us.
我們仍然在努力 尋求那早已存在的東西
Last words.
發出最後的聲音
Out.
出去了
Did you get all that?
你們準備好了嗎？
Yeah.
是的
l got it, Jim.
準備好了
Come on. Let's get some tacos.
讓我們再次沉浸在音樂中吧
1971年，巴黎
Death.
死亡
lt's not so bad.
對人來說是
- Jim? - l love my girl.
最好不過的事了
Jim, is that you?
吉姆，是你嗎？
l knew it was you, Jim Morrison. l always know when it's you.
我知道肯定是你，我知道是你
Come on, baby. Get out of the tub.
好了，乖孩子
Come on. Mama will dry you off.
把水龍頭關上吧
Just stop joking around, you hear me? Just cut it out.
來吧，媽媽會幫你擦乾的
Was it all right, Jim?
別開玩笑了，你聽見我的話了嗎？
Did you enjoy it when it came...
這下你該高興了吧？
just like you said you would?
別再開玩笑了
拉雪茲公墓
喬治比才
莎拉伯恩哈特
They are waiting to take us...
人們都在等待
into the severed garden.
終有一天會走進那座墳
You know how pale and wanton thrillful comes death...
夥伴們呼喚這個奇妙的靈魂復活
in the strange hour...
宣稱是他們
unannounced, unplanned for...
發現了這塊瑰寶
like a scary, over-friendly guest you've brought to bed.
他毫不恐懼，坦然的走向死亡
Death makes angels of us all and give us wings...
他變成了天使，輕盈地飄過人間
where we had shoulders smooth as ravens' claws.
不再有金錢，也不再有優質大麻
No more money, no more fancy dress.
在另外一個王國中
This other kingdom seems by far the best...
繼續干其他的事情，餘下的人們 生活將刻板而單調
until its other jaw reveals incest...
女人和姑娘們
and loose obedience to a vegetable law.
會永遠懷念
l will not go.
她們曾經擁有過的
l prefer a feast of friends to the giant family.
親切的歌聲
吉姆據說死於心力衰竭 時年27歲
3年後帕姆拉亦隨他而去
時間軸調整、中英字幕合併@致遠淡泊